<rdf:RDF
    xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
    xmlns:rdfa="http://www.w3.org/ns/rdfa#"
    xmlns:skos="http://www.w3.org/2004/02/skos/core#"
    xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
    xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/">
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/René_Emilio_Ponce">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">René Emilio Ponce (1947 – May 2, 2011) was a senior military officer in the Salvadoran Army during the nation's civil war, and minister of defense from 1990 to 1993. As head of the army’s joint chiefs of staff he was linked to the killing of six Jesuit priests in 1989, known as the murdered scholars of UCA. Ponce died on May 2, 2011 at a military hospital in San Salvador.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Rene ponce</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">René Ponce</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Rene Emilio Ponce</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/René_Emilio_Ponce"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">René Emilio Ponce</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Society_of_Jesus">
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jesuit missionary</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Society of Jesus, The</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Societas Jesu</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jesuit Order</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Loyolites</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jesuit Apologetic</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Compania de Jesus</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Society of Jesus (Jesuits)</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Fathers of the Society of Jesus</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jesuit priest</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jesuits</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Compañía de Jesús</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jesuit vocation</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jezuit Society</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Society of Jesuits</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">History of the (1814-1912) Jesuits</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">History of the (pre-1750) Jesuits</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jesuit society</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Society of jesus</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jesuit missionaries</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The Society of Jesus (Latin: Societas Iesu, S.J., SJ or SI) is a male religious congregation of the Catholic Church. The members are called Jesuits. The society is engaged in evangelization and apostolic ministry in 112 nations on six continents. Jesuits work in education (founding schools, colleges, universities and seminaries), intellectual research, and cultural pursuits. Jesuits also give retreats, minister in hospitals and parishes, and promote social justice and ecumenical dialogue. Ignatius of Loyola founded the society after being wounded in battle and experiencing a religious conversion. He composed the Spiritual Exercises to help others follow the teachings of Jesus Christ. In 1534, Ignatius and six other young men, including Francis Xavier and Peter Faber, gathered and professed vows of poverty, chastity, and later obedience, including a special vow of obedience to the Pope in matters of mission direction and assignment. Ignatius's plan of the order's organization was approved by Pope Paul III in 1540 by a bull containing the "Formula of the Institute". Ignatius was a nobleman who had a military background, and the members of the society were supposed to accept orders anywhere in the world, where they might be required to live in extreme conditions. Accordingly, the opening lines of the founding document declared that the Society was founded for "whoever desires to serve as a soldier of God (Spanish: "todo el que quiera militar para Dios"), to strive especially for the defense and propagation of the faith and for the progress of souls in Christian life and doctrine." Jesuits are thus sometimes referred to colloquially as "God's Soldiers", "God's Marines", or "the Company", which evolved fromreferences to Ignatius' history as a soldier and the society's commitment to accepting orders anywhere and to endure any conditions. The Society participated in the Counter-Reformation and, later, in the implementation of the Second Vatican Council. The Society of Jesus is consecrated under the patronage of Madonna Della Strada, a title of the Blessed Virgin Mary, and it is led by a Superior General. The Society of Jesus on October 3, 2016 announced that Superior General Adolfo Nicolás' resignation was officially accepted and that a successor would be chosen the following week. On October 14, the 36th General Congregation of the Society of Jesus elected Father Arturo Sosa as its thirty-first Superior General. The headquarters of the society, its General Curia, is in Rome. The historic curia of St. Ignatius is now part of the Collegio del Gesù attached to the Church of the Gesù, the Jesuit Mother Church. In 2013, Jorge Mario Bergoglio became the first Jesuit Pope, taking the name Pope Francis.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jesus, The Society of</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jesuit</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Black Robes</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Company of Jesus</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">US Assistancy</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jesuit Fathers</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jesuit Generals Prior to the Suppression</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Society_of_Jesus"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Societas Iesu</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Brothers of the Society of Jesus</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">History of the (1773-1814) Jesuits</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jesuites</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jesuit priests</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jesuit order</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jesuits in Canada</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Society of Jesus</skos:prefLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Order of Jesuits</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Societas Jesus</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jesuit Brothers</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">The Jesuits</skos:altLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/José_Abello_Silva">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">José Rafael Abello Silva (alias: "Mono Abello") was a top-ranking member of Colombia's notorious Medellín Cartel. He was considered among the major drug traffickers in the Santa Marta region and the reputed chief of Caribbean coast operations on the cartel's behalf. During January 1987, Abello was included in a group of 128 major narcotics figures whose capture was ordered by President Virgilio Barco. Although he was captured in Barranquilla during that same month, he was released shortly thereafter, apparently with the help of Miguel Pinedo Barros, a senator in La Guajira and reputed protector of cocaine traffickers. He was indicted by a United States federal grand jury in Tulsa, Oklahoma, during 1987 on charges of conspiring to import and distribute cocaine into the United States. The Drug Enforcement Administration said that Abello "was considered a major transporter for the Medellín cartel," responsible for "major shipments of cocaine and marijuana into the states." Abello was the cartel's chief of operations for Colombia's northern coast. Specifically, the DEA estimated that Abello's trafficking ring was responsible for the importation of more than 1,700 pounds of cocaine into the United States.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jose Rafael Abello Silva</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jose Abello</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jose Abello Silva</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">José Abello</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/José_Abello_Silva"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">José Abello Silva</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Álvaro_Fayad">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Álvaro Fayad</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Álvaro_Fayad"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Álvaro Fayad Delgado</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Alvaro Fayad</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Álvaro Fayad Delgado “The Turk” (in Spanish, el Turco) was a Colombian guerrilla, co-founder and leader of the 19th of April movement (M-19), founded in 1970.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Search_Bloc">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The Search Bloc (Spanish: Bloque de Búsqueda) was the name of three different special operations units of the National Police of Colombia (Policía Nacional de Colombia). They were originally organized with a focus on capturing or killing highly dangerous individuals or groups of individuals.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Bloque de Busqueda</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Bloque de Búsqueda</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Bloque de búsqueda</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Search Block</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Search_Bloc"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Search Bloc</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Administrative_Department_of_Security">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The Administrative Department of Security (Spanish: Departamento Administrativo de Seguridad, DAS) was the Security Service agency of Colombia, which was also responsible for border and immigration services. It was dissolved on 31 October 2011 as part of a wider Executive Reform, and was replaced by the Agencia Nacional de Inteligencia Colombiana (ANIC).</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Administrative department of security</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Departamento Administrativo de Seguridad</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Departamento administrativo de seguridad</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Colombian intelligence</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Administrative_Department_of_Security"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Administrative Department of Security</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Miguel_Maza_Márquez">
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Miguel Maza Marquez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">General (R) Miguel Alfredo Maza Márquez (born in Santa Marta, Magdalena) is a retired Colombian general, and former director of the Administrative Department of Security (DAS).</skos:definition>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Miguel_Maza_Márquez"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Miguel Maza Márquez</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Víctor_Manuel_Mejía_Múnera">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Víctor Manuel Mejía Múnera</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Víctor_Manuel_Mejía_Múnera"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Victor Manuel Mejia Munera</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Víctor Manuel Mejía Múnera (July 11, 1959 – April 29, 2008), aka "El Mellizo (the twin)" or "Pablo Arauca", was a Colombian drug lord and former paramilitary leader along twin brother Miguel Ángel of the United Self-Defense Forces of Colombia (AUC) commanding the Bloque Vencedores de Arauca which demobilized in 2006. Mejia-Munera along with twin brother Miguel Ángel were wanted by the United States and Colombian governments on charges related to the Illegal drug trade in Colombia and forming illegal paramilitary groups for terrorist purposes. On December 5, 2007 an operation led by Colombian National Police DIJIN police intelligence captured members of his personal army of hitmen known as "Los Nevados", mostly former members of the paramilitary groups.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Waldemar_Franklin_Quintero">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Colonel Valdemar Franklin Quintero (January 26, 1941 – August 18, 1989) was the commander of the Colombian National Police in Antioquia Province. Franklin had led several major raids which resulted in the seizure of multiple tons of cocaine. He was murdered by the Medellín cartel in Medellín because of these drug seizures and his refusal to talk with the cartel. He successfully thwarted an attempt to kill Luis Carlos Galán, a Colombian journalist and presidential candidate, when an RPG was launched at Galán. The cartel formally took responsibility for the slaying of the police commander by calling a series of local radio stations. The caller, who identified himself as a person from the "The Extraditables", said "We, the Extraditables, claim responsibility for the murder of Col. Valdemar Franklin in response to the repression committed and the government's refusal to have a dialogue with us". Pablo Escobar, a major Colombian drug lord, had allegedly ordered the murder of Franklin on the day of the death of Luis Carlos Galán. On 18 August 1989 (the same day in which the Colombian politician Luis Carlos Galán was murdered), at the age of 46, Franklin left his residence in a chauffeur-driven car. When the vehicle was 450 feet from the compound, its route was blocked by another car and several gunmen emerged, according to officials. Various witnesses said that Franklin's car was destroyed by gunfire and the interior was covered in blood. One eye-witness stated to a local radio station, "They fired without mercy for several minutes at the colonel, who was hit more than a hundred times". That witness also said that the chauffeur was injured in the ambush. He is portrayed by the actor Mauricio Figueroa as the character Osvaldo Quintana in the colombian TV Series Escobar, el patrón del mal.</skos:definition>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Waldemar_Franklin_Quintero"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Waldemar Franklin Quintero</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/John_Jairo_Velásquez">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">John Jairo Velásquez</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Jairo_Velásquez"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jhon Jairo Velásquez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">John Jairo Velásquez Vásquez (Yarumal, Antioquia, April 15, 1962) also known by the alias Popeye, is an ex-sicario (hitman) that was part of the criminal structure of the Medellin Cartel until his delivery to the Colombian justice system in 1992. Within this structure he was a lieutenant commanding half of the sicarios. He was one of the members of the inner circle of Pablo Escobar, the head of the criminal organization calling itself The Extraditables.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Juan_Matta-Ballesteros">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Juan Matta-Ballesteros</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Juan_Matta-Ballesteros"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Juan Ramon Matta Bellesteros</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Juan Ramon Matta</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Juan Ramon Matta Ballesteros</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Juan Ramón Matta-Ballesteros (January 12, 1945) (commonly known as Ramón Matta) is a former drug lord with ties to the Colombian Medellin Cartel and the Guadalajara Cartel. In April 1988, he was taken from his Tegucigalpa home by United States Marshals, sent to the United States for trial, and convicted of the kidnap and assassination of Enrique Camarena, as well as other charges. Matta is serving 12 life sentences at the United States Penitentiary, Canaan, a high-security federal prison in Pennsylvania.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Juan_Carlos_Ramírez_Abadía">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Juan Carlos Ramírez Abadía</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Juan_Carlos_Ramírez_Abadía"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Juan Carlos Ramirez Abadia</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Juan Carlos Ramirez-Abadia</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Chupeta</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Juan Carlos Ramírez Abadía (Alias "Chupeta") (born February 16, 1963 in Palmira, Colombia) is a drug trafficker who, until his capture, was one of the leaders of the North Valley Cartel (Norte del Valle Cartel), who was wanted on drug smuggling, murder and RICO charges in the United States of America. In addition to the trafficking of cocaine, it is believed Abadia also participated in money laundering and trafficking of heroin. Through Abadias' illegal enterprise, he has amassed a fortune estimated at $1.8 billion by the US Department of State. He has been cited as "... one of the most powerful and most elusive drug traffickers in Colombia" by Adam J. Szubin, Director of the U.S. Department of the Treasury's Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC). On August 7, 2007 Ramírez Abadía was arrested in São Paulo, Brazil, in an exclusive area called Aldeia da Serra. On March 13, 2008, the Supreme Federal Court of Brazil granted his extradition to the United States. "Chupeta" was extradited to the United States on Friday, August 22, 2008.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Fabio_Ochoa_Vásquez">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Fabio Ochoa Vásquez (born May 2, 1957) was a leading member of the Medellín cocaine trafficking cartel, along with his older brothers Juan David and Jorge Luis. His role briefly made him a billionaire. After serving a brief prison term in Colombia, he was arrested and extradited to the US in 1999 and is serving a 30 year term in US federal prison.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Fabio Ochoa Vazquez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Fabio Ochoa Vasquez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Fabio Ochoa Vázquez</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fabio_Ochoa_Vásquez"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Fabio Ochoa Vásquez</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Óscar_Arias">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Óscar Arias Sánchez (born 13 September 1940 in Heredia, Costa Rica) was President of Costa Rica from 1986 to 1990 and from 2006 to 2010. He received the Nobel Peace Prize in 1987 for his efforts to end the Central American crisis. He is also a recipient of the Albert Schweitzer Prize for Humanitarianism and a trustee of Economists for Peace and Security. In 2003, he was elected to the Board of Directors of the International Criminal Court's Trust Fund for Victims.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Oscar Arias Sanchez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Oscar Arias</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Óscar_Arias"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Óscar Arias Sánchez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Oscar Arias Sánchez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Oscar Arias Sanches</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Arias Sanchez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Óscar Rafael de Jesús Arias Sánchez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Óscar Arias</skos:prefLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Arias sanchez</skos:altLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Daniel_Rendón_Herrera">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Daniel Rendón Herrera</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniel_Rendón_Herrera"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Don Mario</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Daniel Rendon Herrera</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Daniel Rendón Herrera (alias Don Mario; born 1966) is a Colombian drug lord. He was captured on April 15, 2009 while hiding in a jungle. He was once the leader of the Los Gaitanistas drug trafficking parmilitary gang, formerly known as Auto-defensas Gaitanistas (Gaitanist Self-Defence Group), and founding member of the "Los Urabeños" criminal gang.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Patriotic_Union_(Colombia)">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Patriotic Union (Colombia)</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Patriotic_Union_(Colombia)"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Patriotic Union Party</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Union Patriotica (Colombia)</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Unión Patriótica (Colombia)</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The Patriotic Union or UP (in Spanish: Unión Patriótica) is a leftist Colombian political party. It was founded by the FARC and the Colombian Communist Party in 1985, as part of the peace negotiations that the guerrillas held with the Conservative Belisario Betancur administration. The party was subject to political violence from drug lords, paramilitaries and security forces agents during the mid-1980s, leading to its eventual decline, virtual disappearance and extermination. After September 2002, the UP no longer had formal and legal representative status as a political party, nonetheless in July 2013 the Council of State of Colombia gave the UP its political status back, habilitating its members to run for office.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Carlos_Pizarro_Leongómez">
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Carlos Pizarro Leongomez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Carlos Pizarro</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Carlos Pizarro Leongómez (6 June 1951 – 26 April 1990) was the fourth commander of the Colombian guerrilla group 19th of April Movement (Movimiento 19 de Abril) (M-19). Pizarro later ran for president of Colombia after the demobilization of M-19 that transformed the group into the political party, M-19 Democratic Alliance (Alianza Democrática M-19) (AD/M-19). Pizarro was assassinated on 26 April 1990.</skos:definition>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carlos_Pizarro_Leongómez"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Carlos Pizarro Leongómez</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Jorge_Enrique_Rodríguez">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Jorge Enrique Rodríguez</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jorge_Enrique_Rodríguez"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jorge Enrique Rodriguez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Jorge Enrique Rodríguez Mendieta known by his nom de guerre Iván Vargas (born c. 1963) is a Colombian guerrilla leader member of the Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia (FARC-EP), former commander of the 24th Front of the Middle Magdalena Bloc of the FARC-EP. Vargas was arrested in late 2004 in the city of Bucaramanga by Colombian authorities and extradited to the United States on November 3, 2007 on charges of narcotrafficking.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Gustavo_Gaviria">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Gustavo Gaviria</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gustavo_Gaviria"/>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Gustavo de Jesús Gaviria Rivero (25 January 1949, in Pereira – 12 August 1990) was the cousin of Colombian drug trafficker Pablo Escobar and financial head of the Medellín cartel.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Roberto_D&apos;Aubuisson">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Roberto D'Aubuisson Arrieta (August 23, 1943 – February 20, 1992) was a Salvadoran solider, extreme right-wing politician and death-squad leader. In 1981, he co-founded and became the first leader of the Nationalist Republican Alliance (ARENA) and served as President of El Salvador's Constituent Assembly from 1982 to 1983. He was a candidate for President in 1984, losing in the second round to José Napoleón Duarte. After ARENA's loss in the 1985 legislative elections, he stepped down in favor of Alfredo Cristiani and was awarded the honorary post of party president for life. He was named by the UN-created Truth Commission for El Salvador as having ordered the assassination of Archbishop Romero.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">D'Aubuisson</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Roberto D'Aubuisson Arrieta</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Roberto d'Aubuisson</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Roberto D’Aubuisson</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roberto_D&apos;Aubuisson"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Roberto D'Aubuisson</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Gilberto_Rodríguez_Orejuela">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Gilberto José Rodríguez Orejuela (born on January 30, 1939, in Mariquita, Tolima) is a Colombian drug lord, formerly one of the leaders of the Cali Cartel, based in the city of Cali.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Gilberto Rodriguez Orjuela</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Gilberto Rodriquez-Orejuela</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Gilberto Rodriguez Orejuela</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Gilberto Rodriguez-Orjuela</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Gilberto Rodreguez Orjuela</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gilberto_Rodríguez_Orejuela"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Gilberto Rodríguez Orejuela</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Cali_Cartel">
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Cartel de Cali</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Cali Cartel</skos:prefLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Cali drug cartel</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Cali mafia</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Cartel De Cali</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cali_Cartel"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Cali cartel</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The Cali Cartel was a drug cartel based in southern Colombia, around the city of Cali and the Valle del Cauca Department. Its founders were the Rodríguez Orejuela brothers, Gilberto and Miguel, and José Santacruz Londoño, also known as "Chepe". They broke away from Pablo Escobar and his Medellin associates in the late 1980s when Hélmer Herrera, also known as "Pacho", joined what became a four-man executive board that ran the cartel. With connections to British mercenaries, allies among countries, countless spies and informants in the government and its vast intelligence and surveillance network throughout the city of Santiago de Cali, the cartel was once renowned and compared to the Russian KGB by the American DEA, calling it "The most powerful crime syndicate in history", later called "The Cali KGB". At the height of the Cali Cartel's reign, they were cited as having control over 90% of the world's cocaine market and for being directly responsible for the growth of the cocaine market in Europe, controlling 90% of the market. By the mid-1990s, the trafficking empire of the Cali Cartel was a multibillion-dollar enterprise.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Las Chemas</skos:altLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Jaime_Pardo_Leal">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Jaime Pardo Leal</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jaime_Pardo_Leal"/>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Jaime Pardo Leal (March 28, 1941  – October 11, 1987) was the candidate of the Patriotic Union for the presidency of Colombia in the 1986 elections. Members of the Patriotic Union became the target of multiple death threats and assassination attempts. Pardo Leal himself, after running for president in 1986, was assassinated by a 14-year-old on October 11, 1987, who was later killed as well. Drug lord José Gonzalo Rodríguez Gacha, also known as "the Mexican", was apparently involved in the murder as a sponsor. The Colombian Communist Party newspaper Voz published a report in which it linked members of the Colombian military to Rodríguez Gacha. By 1988, the UP announced that more than 500 of its members, including Pardo Leal and four congressmen, had been assassinated to date. Unidentified gunmen later attacked more than 100 of the UP's local candidates in the six months preceding the March 1988 elections. An April 1988 report by Amnesty International charged that members of the Colombian military and government would be involved in what was called a "deliberate policy of political murder" of UP militants and others. The terms of that accusation were rejected and deemed to be an inaccurate exaggeration by the administration of Virgilio Barco Vargas. By 2003-2004, the official legal representatives of a partial number of UP victims presented a concrete death toll of about 1,163 to the Inter-American Commission on Human Rights (IACHR), of which 450 (38%) were attributed directly to paramilitary groups. The breakdown of the remainder was not publicly specified.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Isabel_Martínez_de_Perón">
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Isabel Martínez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">María Estela Martínez Cartas</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Isabel Martínez de Perón</skos:prefLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Isabel Peron</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Maria Estela Martinez de Peron</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">María Estela Martínez Cartas de Perón</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Maria Estela Martinez Cartas</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Isabel_Martínez_de_Perón"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Isabel Martínez Cartes de Perón</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Isabel Martinez Cartes de Peron</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">María Estela Martínez de Perón</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Isabel Martinez de Peron</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Isabelita Perón</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Isabel Perón</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Isabel de Perón</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">María Estela Martínez Cartas de Perón (born 4 February 1931), better known as Isabel Martínez de Perón (Spanish pronunciation: [isaˈβel marˈtines]) or Isabel Perón, is a former President of Argentina. She was the third wife of President Juan Perón. During her husband's third term as president from 1973 to 1974, Isabel served as both vice president and First Lady. Following her husband's death in office in 1974, Isabel served as president of Argentina from 1 July 1974 to 24 March 1976. She holds the distinction of being the first female president of any country in the world. In 2007 an Argentine judge ordered her arrest over the forced disappearance of an activist in February 1976, on the grounds that the disappearance was authorized by her signing of decrees allowing Argentina's armed forces to take action against "subversives". She was arrested near her home in Spain on 12 January 2007. Spanish courts subsequently refused her extradition to Argentina.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Isabel Martinez de Perón</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Maria Estela Martinez Cartas de Peron</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">María Estela Martínez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Isabel de Peron</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Maria Estela Martinez De Peron</skos:altLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Diego_León_Montoya_Sánchez">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Diego León Montoya Sánchez</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Diego_León_Montoya_Sánchez"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">DIEGO LEON MONTOYA SANCHEZ</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Diego Montoya Sanchez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Don Diego</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Diego Leon Montoya Sanchez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Diego León Montoya Sánchez (born January 11, 1958/1961), also known as Don Diego, is a Colombian former crime boss and leader of the Norte del Valle drug cartel. On October 25, 2002, Montoya was listed as a Specially Designated Narcotics Trafficker on the United States Department of Treasury's Specially Designated National List (also known as La Lista Clinton). On May 6, 2004, he became the 478th fugitive listed by the United States' Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) on the Ten Most Wanted Fugitives list. He was also wanted in Colombia, where authorities started numerous operations to capture him or his interests. The U.S. Department of State's Narcotics Rewards Program offered a reward of up to $5 million for information leading directly to Montoya's arrest or conviction, the highest amount offered at the time for a non-terrorist fugitive, effectively making the priority of his capture second only to that of Osama bin Laden. In January 2007, Montoya's brother and co-leader of the cartel, Eugenio, was captured in Colombia. Colombian authorities announced on September 10 that they had arrested Montoya himself in the west of the country after a long manhunt. On December 12, 2008, Montoya was extradited to Miami on a D.E.A. helicopter, marking the final demise of the Norte del Valle Cartel.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Manuel_Noriega">
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Manuel Antonio Noriega</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">General Noriega</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Noriega Moreno, Manuel Antonio</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Manuel Noriega Morena</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Manuel Antonio Noriega Moreno (Spanish pronunciation: [maˈnwel noˈɾjeɣa]; born February 11, 1934) is a former Panamanian politician and military officer. He was military dictator of Panama from 1983 to 1989, when he was removed from power by the United States during the invasion of Panama. From the 1950s until shortly before the U.S. invasion, Noriega worked closely with the U.S. Central Intelligence Agency. Noriega was one of the CIA's most valued intelligence sources, as well as one of the primary conduits for illicit weapons, military equipment and cash destined for US-backed counter-insurgency forces throughout Central and South America. Noriega was also a major cocaine trafficker, something which his U.S. intelligence handlers were aware of for years, but allowed because of his usefulness for their covert military operations in Latin America. In 1988, Noriega was indicted by the United States on drug trafficking charges in Miami, Florida. During the 1989 U.S. invasion of Panama, he was removed from power, captured, detained as a prisoner of war, and flown to the United States. Noriega was tried on eight counts of drug trafficking, racketeering, and money laundering in April 1992. On September 16, 1992, he was sentenced to 40 years in prison (which was later reduced to 30 years). Noriega's U.S. prison sentence ended in September 2007; pending the outcome of extradition requests by both Panama and France, for convictions in absentia for murder in 1995 and money laundering in 1999. France was granted its extradition request in April 2010. He arrived in Paris on April 27, 2010, and after the re-trial that is a rule in France after any in absentia sentence, he was found guilty and sentenced to seven years in jail in July 2010. A conditional release was granted on September 23, 2011, for Noriega to be extradited to serve 20 years in Panama. He returned to Panama on December 11, 2011.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Manuel Noriega Moreno</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Manuel Antonio Noriega Morena</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Manuel Noreiga</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Manny Noriega</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Manuel Noregia</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Manuel_Noriega"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Manuel Antonio Noriega Moreno</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Manuel noriega</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Manuel Noriega</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Juan_David_Ochoa_Vásquez">
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Juan Vasquez (drug lord)</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Juan David Ochoa</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Juan David Ochoa Vasquez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Juan David Ochoa Vásquez (c. 1949 – 25 July 2013) was a Colombian drug trafficker and one of the founders of the Medellín Cartel, a major drug trafficking cartel based in the city of Medellín. Juan David was the elder brother of Jorge Luis and Fabio Ochoa Vásquez, powerful figures inside the Medellín Cartel. In 1991, Juan David Ochoa Vásquez, together with his brother Jorge Luis, turned themselves in to the Colombian government in order to receive the benefits of collaborating with the judicial system. Juan David Ochoa negotiated a surrender and was imprisoned in a medium security prison outside Medellín. In January 1996, as the result of a sentence plea bargain with the state, Juan David Ochoa Vásquez was released from prison after serving five years.</skos:definition>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Juan_David_Ochoa_Vásquez"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Juan David Ochoa Vásquez</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Miguel_Ángel_Mejía_Múnera">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Miguel Ángel Mejía Múnera</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Miguel_Ángel_Mejía_Múnera"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Miguel Angel Melchor Mejia Munera</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Miguel Angel Mejia Munera</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Miguel Ángel Mejía Múnera aka "El Mellizo" or "Pablo Mejía" (born July 11, 1959) is a presumed Colombian drug lord and former paramilitary leader. Along with brother Víctor Manuel he created a drug cartel called "Los Nevados" out of a former paramilitary which they bought for US$ million dollars. The cartel buys illegal drugs from Daniel Barrera Barrera another drug lord working along with both the Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia (FARC) as well as paramilitaries. . The brothers have also been know to employ many ex-military and special body guards like Francisco Rivas Gonzales "Superman" who has disappeared, and believed to be somewhere in Mexico or Central America. According to the US Department of State the "Mellizos" have managed multi-ton cocaine transportation routes from the Caribbean Region of Colombia to the United States and Europe since the late 1990s. Their transportation and money laundering organization was conservatively estimated to have transported approximately 68 tons of cocaine over a two-year time period. In 2003 their organization was dismantled during a U.S. multi-jurisdictional effort called Operation Journey. That operation resulted in the seizure of 25 tons of cocaine and the arrest of 43 individuals, however, the Mejía-Múnera brothers escaped. Mejía-Múnera was also involved in the Paramilitary Peace Process until he failed to turn himself in to the Government of Colombia in August 2006. In 2003, Miguel and brother Victor Mejía-Múnera were indicted in the Southern District of Florida for conspiracy to import cocaine. The US Department of State is offering a reward of up to US$5 million for information leading to the arrest and/or conviction of Mejia-Munera. Colombian minister of Defense Juan Manuel Santos informed that Mejia-Munera had five arrest warrants and one extradition petition by the United States. Colombian authorities also related the Cocaleros protest of the weeks before his death in the municipality of Tarazá to Mejía-Múnera as a strategy to distract authorities and escape.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Hernando_Durán_Dussán">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Hernando Durán Dussán</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hernando_Durán_Dussán"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Hernando Duran Dussan</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Hernando Durán Dussán (Bogotá, 1920 – Kuala Lumpur, 4 September 1998) was a Colombian lawyer and politician. He was the Mayor of Bogotá and a candidate for the Presidency in 1990.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Roberto_de_Jesús_Escobar_Gaviria">
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roberto_de_Jesús_Escobar_Gaviria"/>
    <skos:definition>Roberto de Jesús Escobar Gaviria (born January 13, 1947), nicknamed El Osito (Little Bear), was the brother of the drug kingpin, Pablo Escobar, and the former accountant and co-founder of the Medellín Cartel, which was responsible for up to 80 percent of the cocaine smuggled into the United States.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Little Bear</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">El Osito</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Roberto de Jesús Escobar Gaviria</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Diana_Turbay">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Diana Turbay Quintero (March 9, 1950 – January 25, 1991) was a Colombian journalist kidnapped by the Medellín Cartel and killed by the Colombia National Police during a rescue attempt. Her story has been portrayed in a non-fiction book by Gabriel García Márquez and onscreen.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Diana Turbay Quintero</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Diana Consuelo Turbay Quintero</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Diana_Turbay"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Diana Turbay</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/George_Jung">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">George Jung</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/George_Jung"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Boston George</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">George Jacob Jung (born August 6, 1942), nicknamed Boston George and El Americano, was a major player in the cocaine trade in the United States in the 1970s and early 1980s. Jung was a part of the Medellín Cartel, which was responsible for up to 89 percent of the cocaine smuggled into the United States. He specialized in the smuggling of cocaine from Colombia on a large scale. His life story was portrayed in the biopic Blow (2001), starring Johnny Depp. Jung was released from prison on June 2, 2014, after serving nearly 20 years for drug-smuggling.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Muerte_a_Secuestradores">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Muerte a Secuestradores</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Muerte_a_Secuestradores"/>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Muerte a Secuestradores (English: Death to Kidnappers) or MAS, was a Colombian paramilitary group supported by drug cartels, U.S. corporations, Colombian politicians, and wealthy landowners during the 1980s in order to protect their economic interests and fight kidnapping. Muerte a Secuestradores has assassinated political opponents and community organizers, and waged counterinsurgency warfare against guerrilla movements such as the FARC-EP and the M-19.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Directorate_of_Criminal_Investigation_and_Interpol">
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Central directorate of the judicial police and intelligence</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Central Directorate of the Judicial Police and Intelligence</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">DIJIN</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The Directorate of Criminal Investigation and Interpol Spanish: Dirección de Investigación Criminal e Interpol (DICI), formerly the Central Directorate of the Judicial Police and Intelligence (Spanish: Dirección Central de Policía Judicial e Inteligencia, DIJIN) is a Directorate of the Colombian National Police in charge of judicial and certain intelligence tasks.</skos:definition>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Directorate_of_Criminal_Investigation_and_Interpol"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Directorate of Criminal Investigation and Interpol</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Mario_Revollo_Bravo">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Mario Revollo Bravo</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mario_Revollo_Bravo"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Mario Cardinal Revollo Bravo</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Mario Revollo Bravo (September 19, 1919 - November 3, 1995) was a Cardinal and Archbishop of Bogotá in the Roman Catholic Church.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Hélmer_Herrera">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Francisco Hélmer Herrera Buitrago also known as "Pacho" and "H7", (August 24, 1951 in Palmira, Valle del Cauca – November 4, 1998 in Palmira, Valle del Cauca) was a Colombian drug trafficker, fourth in command in the Cali Cartel. Believed to be the son of Benjamin Herrera Zuleta.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Helmer Herrera</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hélmer_Herrera"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Hélmer Herrera</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Texaco">
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">TEXACO</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Texpet</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Texaco, Inc. ("The Texas Company") is an American oil subsidiary of Chevron Corporation. Its flagship product is its fuel "Texaco with Techron". It also owns the Havoline motor oil brand. Texaco was an independent company until its refining operations merged into Chevron Corporation in 2001, at which time most of its station franchises were divested to the Shell Oil Company. It began as the Texas Fuel Company, founded in 1901 in Beaumont, Texas, by Joseph S. Cullinan, Thomas J. Donoghue, Walter Benona Sharp, and Arnold Schlaet upon the discovery of oil at Spindletop. For many years, Texaco was the only company selling gasoline under the same brand name in all 50 US states, as well as Canada, making it the most truly national brand among its competitors. It was also one of the Seven Sisters which dominated the global petroleum industry from the mid-1940s to the 1970s. Its current logo features a white star in a red circle (a reference to the lone star of Texas), leading to the long-running advertising jingles "You can trust your car to the man who wears the star" and "Star of the American Road." The company was headquartered in Harrison, New York, near White Plains, prior to the merger with Chevron. Texaco gasoline comes with Techron, an additive developed by Chevron, as of 2005, replacing the previous CleanSystem3. The Texaco brand is strong in the U.S., Latin America and West Africa. It has a presence in Europe as well; for example, it is a well-known retail brand in the UK, with around 1,100 Texaco-branded service stations.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Texas Oil Company</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Texas Fuel Company</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Texaco Company</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Texas Oil</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">The Texas Fuel Company</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Texaco, Inc.</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Sky Chief</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">The Texas Company</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Texaco Corporation</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Texas Company</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Texaco Online</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Texaco Petroleum Company</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Texas Petroleum</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Texaco Inc.</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Texaco"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Texaco Petroleum</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Texaco</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Ernesto_Báez">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Ernesto Báez</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ernesto_Báez"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Ernesto Baez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Iván Roberto Duque</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Iván Roberto Duque Gaviria aka Ernesto Báez (born May 9, 1955 in Aguadas, Caldas) is a Colombian paramilitary leader former member of the demobilized United Self-Defense Forces of Colombia (AUC). Duque-Gaviria graduated as a lawyer from the Universidad de Caldas. Duque Gaviria began his career as a member of the Colombian Liberal Party, he was democratically elected as Mayor of the municipality of La Merced and later worked for the Empresas Públicas de Manizales. In 1982 founded the Asociación Campesina de Ganaderos y Agricultores del Magdalena Medio, ACDEGAM (Ranchers and Farmers of the Middle Magdalena Peasant Association) in Puerto Boyaca presumably as a facade for the creation of paramilitary groups for the troubled region. Duque Gaviria became an adviser to this organization and was later arrested in connection to paramilitary organizations accused by the Attorney General of Colombia. He was arrested and imprisoned at La Modelo Maximum Security Prison under assassination and conformation of illegal paramilitary groups charges.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Virgilio_Barco_Vargas">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Virgilio Barco Vargas (17 September 1921 – 20 May 1997) was the 27th President of Colombia serving from 1986 to 1990.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Virgilo Barco Vargas</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Virgilio Barco</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virgilio_Barco_Vargas"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Virgilio Barco Vargas</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Rodrigo_Tovar_Pupo">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Rodrigo Tovar Pupo</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rodrigo_Tovar_Pupo"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jorge 40</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Rodrigo Tovar</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Rodrigo Tovar Pupo, (aka Jorge 40 his nom de guerre) was born in Valledupar, Colombia. He was the leader of the Northern Bloc of the United Self-Defense Forces of Colombia. He demobilized with his two thousand men strong group on March 10, 2006 in La Mesa, Department of Cesar. A laptop computer belonging to Tovar contained information on over 550 murders and started the 2006 Para-political scandal in which several congressmen have been indicted for corruption. From cattle owner and farmer, member of Fenalce and Fedearroz and a public official, pass to command 4500 men of the Northern Bloc that dominate the territories of Cesar, La Guajira, Magdalena, Atlántico and part of both Santander and Norte de Santander Departments. "Just hearing his name instills fear in us", said a member of the Kankuamos, a native community from the Sierra Nevada de Santa Marta who accused him of the assassination of more than 100 of their members. He is also accused of covertly masterminding the repression of the Aseguradoras del Régimen Subsidiado de Salud (ARS) (Spanish for Health Subsidized Regime Insurance) in many municipalities in the Caribbean Region. Besides, he's the alleged ring leader of a loose confederation of drug traffickers operating in the eastern zone of the Sierra Nevada de Santa Marta (a coastal mountain range in northern Colombia) and La Guajira (and adjacent region bordering Venezuela). Due to these activities the United States Government has asked for his extradition in order to bring him to an American court. Jorge 40 was indicted for masterminding the massacre of over 60 natives from the aboriginal Wayuu and Wiwa tribes in La Guajira and Magdalena provinces. They were allegedly executed by the Northern Bloc in 2004. Jorge 40 has also been connected to the death of 21 people in the municipality of Aracataca better known by its fictional name 'Macondo' (Magdalena). The Organization of American States (OAS) denounced Jorge 40's paramilitary activities colluded with local government forces in order to kill eight people in Curumani, Cesar, accusing them to be informants of the ELN guerrilla. The massacre occurred between December 4 and December 5, 2005.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Ernesto_Samper">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Ernesto Samper</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ernesto_Samper"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Samper Pizano, Ernesto</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Ernesto Samper Pizano</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Ernesto Samper Pizano (born 3 August 1950) is a Colombian politician. Samper is a member of the aristocratic, wealthy and influential Samper family. He served as the President of Colombia from 1994 to 1998, representing the Liberal Party. He currently serves as the Secretary General of the Union of South American Nations (UNASUR). He was involved in the 8000 process scandal, which takes its name from the folio number assigned to it by the chief prosecutor's office. The prosecutor charged that money from the Cali Cartel was funneled into Samper's presidential campaign to gain his success in what would have been a very close race after he failed to win by a majority during the first round (Colombia has 2 rounds of elections, unless the first round yields a majority winner). The Colombian House of Representatives acquitted Samper with a vote of 111 to 43, precluding the process.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Alfredo_Cristiani">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Alfredo Félix Cristiani Burkard, popularly known as Alfredo Cristiani (born 22 November 1947) was President of El Salvador from 1989 to 1994.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Alfredo Christiani</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Alfredo Cristiani Burkard</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alfredo_Cristiani"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Alfredo Cristiani</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Wilber_Varela">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Wilber Varela</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wilber_Varela"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Wilber Alirio Varela-Fajardo</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Wilber Alirio Varela Fajardo (November 6, 1957 – January 30, 2008), also known as Jabón ("Soap"), was a Colombian police agent who then became a drug dealer and member of the Norte del Valle Cartel. A Racketeer Influenced and Corrupt Organizations Act indictment was filed in the District Court of the District of Columbia by the Narcotics and Dangerous Drugs Section of the United States Department of Justice Criminal Division against the leaders of the North Valley Cartel, including Varela Fajardo. According to the indictment, the North Valley Cartel exported approximately 500 metric tons of cocaine worth over $10 billion from Colombia to the United States, often through Mexico, between 1990 and 2004. The indictment was unsealed in May 2004. A provisional arrest warrant was issued and was sent to the U.S. Embassy in Bogota. In addition, in March, 2004, a grand jury in the Eastern District of New York indicted Varela on Drug Trafficking Charges. The United States Department of State offered a reward of up to $5 million for information leading to the arrest and/or conviction of Varela Fajardo.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Daniel_Ortega">
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Daniel ortega</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Daniel José Ortega Saavedra</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Daniel Jose Ortega Saavedra</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">José Daniel Ortega Saavedra</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Daniel Ortega</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniel_Ortega"/>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">José Daniel Ortega Saavedra (Spanish pronunciation: [daˈnjel oɾˈteɣa]; born November 11, 1945) is a Nicaraguan politician who has been President of Nicaragua since 2007; previously he was leader of Nicaragua from 1979 to 1990, first as Coordinator of the Junta of National Reconstruction (1979–1985) and then as President (1985–1990). A leader in the socialist Sandinista National Liberation Front (Frente Sandinista de Liberación Nacional, FSLN), his policies in government have seen the implementation of leftist reforms across Nicaragua. Born into a working-class family, from an early age Ortega opposed ruling President Anastasio Somoza Debayle, widely recognized as a dictator, and became involved in the underground movement against his regime. Joining the Sandinistas, he also travelled to Cuba to receive training in guerilla warfare from Fidel Castro's Marxist-Leninist government. After the Nicaraguan Revolution resulted in the overthrow and exile of Somoza's government, Ortega became leader of the ruling multipartisan Junta of National Reconstruction. A Marxist-Leninist, his first period in office was characterized by a controversial program of nationalization, land reform, wealth redistribution and literacy programs. Ortega's relationship with the United States was never very cordial, due to U.S. support for Somoza prior to the revolution. Although the U.S. supplied post-revolution Nicaragua with tens of millions of dollars in economic aid, relations broke down when the Sandinistas supplied weapons to leftist El Salvadoran rebels (something which Ortega later admitted occurred). His government was opposed by the Contras in a vicious civil war; the Contras were funded by the Reagan administration of the United States. A joint peace proposal by the Democratic Speaker of the House Jim Wright and Ronald Reagan helped precipitate a peace agreement at a meeting of five Central American chiefs of state in July 1987, which won Costa Rican President Oscar Arias the Nobel Peace Prize. This led to free elections in which Ortega was defeated by Violeta Chamorro in the 1990 presidential election, but he remained an important figure in Nicaraguan opposition politics, gradually moderating in his political position from Marxism–Leninism to democratic socialism. Ortega was an unsuccessful candidate for president in 1996 and 2001, before winning the 2006 presidential election. In office, he made alliances with fellow Latin American socialists, such as Venezuelan President Hugo Chávez, and under his leadership, Nicaragua joined the Bolivarian Alliance for the Americas.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Daniel Ortega Saavedra</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jose Daniel Ortega Saavedra</skos:altLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Junta_of_National_Reconstruction">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The Junta of National Reconstruction (Junta de Gobierno de Reconstrucción Nacional) officially ruled Nicaragua from July 1979 to January 1985. Effective power was in the hands of the Sandinista National Liberation Front's National Directorate. The Sandinista rebels announced the Junta as its provisional government on June 16, 1979, as the civil war against the Anastasio Somoza Debayle regime entered its final phase. It was composed of five members: a member of the FSLN directorate, Daniel Ortega, two left-wing activists, Sergio Ramírez and Moisés Hassan Morales, and two right-wing representatives, Alfonso Robelo and Violeta Barrios de Chamorro. In the first half of July, United States government envoy William Bowdler pressured the Sandinistas to broaden the junta by adding more members, such as Adolfo Calero, Ismael Reyes, and Mariano Fiallos. After the fall of Somoza, it quickly became apparent to Robelo and Chamorro that they did not have any real power and Chamorro resigned on April 19, 1980, followed by Robelo three days later. On May 18, they were replaced by Arturo Cruz and Rafael Córdova Rivas. Cruz would resign in March 1981, though he agreed for a time to be ambassador to the United States. On March 4, Cruz's appointment to Washington was announced, together with Hassan's departure for the Council of State and Ortega's promotion to Coordinator of the now three-member junta. While the junta may have offered little authority to its non-Sandinista members, the public role did help to solidify Ortega's primacy within the FSLN directorate and enhance Ramírez's prominence. On November 4, 1984, a presidential election was held, which was won by leading junta member and revolutionary Daniel Ortega and his running mate, Sergio Ramírez as vice president. However, some opposition parties boycotted it, claiming unfair conditions. While the Reagan administration and many mainstream United States media outlets alleged the election would be neither free nor fair, numerous electoral watchers affiliated with Western European governments, as well as United States non-governmental organizations, declared the results legitimate. Ortega took office on January 10, and the junta was dissolved.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Junta de Reconstrucción Nacional</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Junta de Gobierno de Reconstrucción Nacional</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Junta de Reconstrucion Nacional</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Government Junta of National Reconstruction</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Junta de Gobierno de Reconstruccion Nacional</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Junta_of_National_Reconstruction"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Junta of National Reconstruction</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/José_Toribio_Merino">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">José Toribio Merino Castro (December 14, 1915 – August 30, 1996) was a Chilean admiral who was one of the principal leaders of the 1973 Chilean coup d'état, along with General Augusto Pinochet of the Army, General Gustavo Leigh of the Air Force, and General César Mendoza of the Carabineros (national police). Together they established a military government that ruled Chile from 1973 until 1990.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jose Toribio Merino</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/José_Toribio_Merino"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">José Toribio Merino</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Supreme_Court_of_Justice_of_Colombia">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The Supreme Court of Colombia (Spanish: Corte Suprema de Justicia de Colombia) in Bogotá is the highest judicial body in civil and penal matters and issues of criminal and civil procedure in Colombia. The Supreme Court of Colombia is the highest authority in regard to the interpretation of administrative law, constitutional law, and the administration of the judiciary The court consists of twenty three magistrates, elected by the same institution in list conformed by the Superior Council of the Judiciary for individual terms of eight years. The court meets at the Palace of Justice in the Bolívar Square of Bogota.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Supreme Court of Colombia</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Colombian Supreme Court of Justice</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Colombian Supreme Court</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Palacio de Justicia de Colombia</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Supreme_Court_of_Justice_of_Colombia"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Supreme Court of Justice of Colombia</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Carlos_Castaño_Gil">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Carlos Castaño Gil</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carlos_Castaño_Gil"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Carlos Castano Gil</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Carlos Castaño Gil (May 16, 1965 – April 16, 2004) was the founder of the Peasant Self-Defense Forces of Córdoba and Urabá (ACCU), an extreme right paramilitary organization in Colombia. Castaño and his brothers Fidel and Vicente founded this group (and its previous incarnations) after their father was kidnapped and killed by the Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia (FARC), in association with other enemies or victims of the guerrillas. The ACCU later became one of the founding members of the United Self-Defense Forces of Colombia (AUC).</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Revolutionary_Socialist_Party_(Peru)">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The Sandinista Popular Army (or People's Army; Ejército Popular Sandinista, EPS) was the military established in 1979 by the new Sandinista government to replace the National Guard, following the overthow of Anastasio Somoza Debayle. In post-Sandinista Nicaragua, it has been remolded into the National Army of Nicaragua. Joaquín Cuadra was chief of staff, serving Defense Minister Humberto Ortega. A draft, called the Patriotic Military Service (Servicio Militar Patriótico), (SMP) was instituted in 1983. It later became Obligatory Military Service (Servicio Militar Obligatorio) (SMO).The special forces Tropas Pablo Ubeda initially came under the Ministry of Interior and then the BLI'S were Created. The SPA's ground forces formed the basis of what is now today the Nicaraguan Army Ground Forces (Fuerzas Terrestres del Ejército de Nicaragua), formed in 1995. They report directly to the Commanding General of the Army.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Ejercito Popular Sandinista</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Sandinist Popular Army</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Sandinista People's Army</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Ejército Popular Sandinista</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Nicaraguan Army</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sandinista_Popular_Army"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Sandinista Popular Army</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bernardo_Jaramillo_Ossa">
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Bernardo Jaramillo</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Bernardo Jaramillo Ossa (born in 1956 in Manizales, Caldas, died in Bogotá, Cundinamarca on March 22, 1990) was a Colombian politician and member of the Colombian Communist Party. Jaramillo started working primarily in the Urabá Antioquia region until 1987 when he assumed the presidency of the Patriotic Union Party (UP) after the assassination of Jaime Pardo.</skos:definition>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bernardo_Jaramillo_Ossa"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Bernardo Jaramillo Ossa</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Diego_Murillo_Bejarano">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Diego Murillo Bejarano</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Diego_Murillo_Bejarano"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Don Berna</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Diego Fernando Murillo Bejarano</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Diego Fernando Murillo Bejarano, also known as Don Berna or Adolfo Paz, is a former leader of the United Self-Defense Forces of Colombia paramilitary group as well as the leader of The Office of Envigado cartel. He started working for the Medellín Cartel and ultimately led its militia wing. After internal vendettas he became one of Pablo Escobar's many enemies and became part of Los Pepes, an organization headed by the Castaño brothers, Carlos and Fidel. The organization controlled a powerful gang of hitmen named La Terraza (The Terrace). He then commanded two paramilitary blocs, the Cacique Nutibara Bloc and the Granada Heroes Bloc. He became third in the chain of command of the AUC and a key player during the peace process in Santa Fe de Ralito, Córdoba between his organization and the government of Colombia, until he was accused by a court of being responsible for the death of a deputy. He then escaped from Santa Fe de Ralito and surrendered to authorities four days later.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Sandinista_National_Liberation_Front">
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">The Sandinista</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sandinista_National_Liberation_Front"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Sandinists</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Frente Sandinista de Liberacion Nacional</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The Sandinista National Liberation Front (Spanish: Frente Sandinista de Liberación Nacional, FSLN) is now a democratic socialist political party in Nicaragua. Its members are called Sandinistas [sandiˈnistas] in both English and Spanish. The party is named after Augusto César Sandino, who led the Nicaraguan resistance against the United States occupation of Nicaragua in the 1930s. The FSLN overthrew Anastasio Somoza Debayle in 1979, ending the Somoza dynasty, and established a revolutionary government in its place. Following their seizure of power, the Sandinistas ruled Nicaragua from 1979 to 1990, first as part of a Junta of National Reconstruction. Following the resignation of centrist members from this Junta, the FSLN took exclusive power in March 1981. They instituted a policy of mass literacy, devoted significant resources to health care, and promoted gender equality. A militia, known as the Contras was formed in 1981 to overthrow the Sandinista government and was funded and trained by the US Central Intelligence Agency. In 1984 elections were held but were boycotted by some opposition parties. The FSLN won the majority of the votes, and those who opposed the Sandinistas won approximately a third of the seats. The civil war between the Contras and the government continued until 1989. After revising the constitution in 1987 and after years of fighting the Contras the FSLN lost what many consider the first truly democratic election in 1990 to Violeta Barrios de Chamorro, but retained a plurality of seats in the legislature. The FSLN remains one of Nicaragua's two leading parties. The FSLN often polls in opposition to the Constitutionalist Liberal Party, or PLC. In the 2006 Nicaraguan general election, former FSLN President Daniel Ortega was re-elected President of Nicaragua with 38.7% of the vote compared to 29% for his leading rival, bringing in the country's second Sandinista government after 16 years of the opposition winning elections. Ortega and the FSLN were re-elected again in the presidential election of November 2011.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Sandinista Liberation Front</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">FSLN</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Sandinista</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Sandanista</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Sandinista Front</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Sandinist Front of National Liberation</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Sandanists</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Sandinistan</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Frente Sandinista de Liberación Nacional</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Sandinist National Liberation Front</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Sandinista National Liberation Front</skos:prefLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Sandinoists</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Sandanistas</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Sandinistas</skos:altLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Schafik_Handal">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Schafik Handal</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Schafik_Handal"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Shafik Handal</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Schafik Hándal</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Shafiq Handal</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Schafik Jorge Hándal</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Schafik Jorge Handal</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Schafik Jorge Handal (Arabic: شفيق جورج حنضل‎‎; October 14, 1930 – January 24, 2006) was a Salvadoran politician. Born in Usulután, he was the son of Arab immigrants from the town of Bethlehem.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Carlos_Andrés_Pérez">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">(This name uses Spanish naming customs: the first or paternal family name is Pérez and the second or maternal family name is Rodríguez.) Carlos Andrés Pérez Rodríguez (27 October 1922 – 25 December 2010), also known as CAP and often referred to as El Gocho (due to his Andean origins), was a Venezuelan politician, President of Venezuela from 1974 to 1979 and again from 1989 to 1993. His first presidency was known as the Saudi Venezuela due to its economic and social prosperity thanks to enormous income from petroleum exportation. However, his second period saw a continuation of the economic crisis of the 1980s, and saw a series of social crises, a popular revolt (denominated Caracazo) and two coup attempts in 1992. In May 1993 he became the first Venezuelan president to be forced out of the office by the Supreme Court, for the embezzlement of 250 million bolívars belonging to a presidential discretionary fund.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Carlos Andres Perez Rodriguez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Carlos Andrés Pérez Rodríguez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Carlos Andres Perez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Carlos Andres Pérez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Andrés pérez</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carlos_Andrés_Pérez"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Carlos Andrés Pérez</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/José_Gonzalo_Rodríguez_Gacha">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">José Gonzalo Rodríguez Gacha (May 14, 1947 – December 15, 1989), also known by the nickname El Mexicano, was a Colombian drug lord who was one of the leaders of the notorious Medellín Cartel along with the Ochoa Brothers and Pablo Escobar. At the height of his criminal career Rodríguez was acknowledged as one of the world's most successful drug dealers. In 1988, Forbes magazine included him in their annual list of the world's billionaires.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">José Gonzalo Rodriguez Gacha</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Gonzalo Rodríguez Gacha</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jose Gonzalo Rodreguez Gacha</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jose Gonzalo Rodriguez Gacha</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Gonzalo Rodriguez Gacha</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/José_Gonzalo_Rodríguez_Gacha"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">José Gonzalo Rodríguez Gacha</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Miguel_Rodríguez_Orejuela">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Miguel Angel Rodríguez Orejuela( born on August 15, 1943, in Mariquita, Tolima) is a Colombian druglord, formerly one of the leaders of the Cali Cartel, based in the city of Cali. He is the younger brother of Gilberto Rodríguez Orejuela. He married Miss Colombia 1974, Marta Lucía Echeverry.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Miguel Rodriguez Orejuela</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Miguel Angel Rodriguez Orjuela</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Miguel_Rodríguez_Orejuela"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Miguel Rodríguez Orejuela</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Alfonso_López_Trujillo">
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Alfonso Lopez Trujillo</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Alfonso Cardinal López Trujillo</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Alfonso López Trujillo (8 November 1935 – 19 April 2008) was a Colombian Cardinal Bishop of the Roman Catholic Church and president of the Pontifical Council for the Family.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Cardinal Lopez Trujillo</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Alfonso López Trujillo</skos:prefLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Cardinal Alfonso Lopez Trujillo</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Cardinal Alfonso López Trujillo</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Alfonso Lopez-Trujillo</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Alfonso Cardinal Lopez Trujillo</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alfonso_López_Trujillo"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Cardinal Trujillo</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Cardinal López Trujillo</skos:altLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Álvaro_Gómez_Hurtado">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Álvaro Gómez Hurtado (May 8, 1919 - November 2, 1995) was a Colombian lawyer, politician, journalist and active member of the Colombian Conservative Party. Gómez was a son of the former President of Colombia, Laureano Gómez. He is mostly remembered for being one of the writers of the Colombian Constitution of 1991 and for running three times for the presidency, but without success. He served separate appointments as ambassador to Italy, the United States and France, beginning in the 1980s.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Alvaro Gomez Hurtado</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Alvaro Gómez Hurtado</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Álvaro_Gómez_Hurtado"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Álvaro Gómez Hurtado</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Fidel_Castaño">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Fidel Castaño</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fidel_Castaño"/>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Fidel Antonio Castaño Gil aka Rambo was a right-wing Colombian drug lord and paramilitary who was among the founders of Los Pepes and the Peasant Self-Defense Forces of Cordoba and Uraba (ACCU), a paramilitary group which ultimately became a member of the larger United Self-Defense Forces of Colombia (AUC) from which he became its leader until his death in 1994. He was also the brother of Vicente Castaño, the presumed chief of the narco-paramilitary group Águilas Negras, and Carlos Castaño Gil, founder and leader of the AUC paramilitary forces until his death.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Fidel Castano Gil</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Fidel Castano</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Fidel Castaño Gil</skos:altLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Guadalajara_Cartel">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The Guadalajara Cartel (Spanish: Cártel de Guadalajara) was a Mexican drug cartel which was formed in the 1980s by Rafael Caro Quintero, Miguel Ángel Félix Gallardo and Ernesto Fonseca Carrillo in order to ship heroin and marijuana to the United States. Among the first of the Mexican drug trafficking groups to work with the Colombian cocaine mafias, the Guadalajara cartel prospered from the cocaine trade.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Guadalajara drug cartel</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Guadalajara_Cartel"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Guadalajara Cartel</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Carlos_Mario_Jiménez">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Carlos Mario Jiménez</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carlos_Mario_Jiménez"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Carlos Mario Jimenez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Javier Montañez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Carlos Mario Jiménez Naranjo aka "Macaco" or Javier Montañez (born February 26, 1966) is a Colombian former drug lord and paramilitary leader. Jimenez was a member of the United Self-Defense Forces of Colombia (AUC) paramilitary group which demobilized between 2005 and 2007. Jimenez ordered the assassination of numerous people in the region of the Santander and North Santander specially in the city of Barrancabermeja where his organization confronted and defeated the National Liberation Army (ELN) for the control of the territory. Jimenez was the commander in chief of the Central Bolívar Bloc of the AUC.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Jesus_Rojas">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Jesus Rojas</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jesus_Rojas"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Antonio Cardenal Caldera</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jesus rojas</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Antonio Cardenal Caldera (1950–1991), also known by the nom de guerre Jesus Rojas (Red Jesus), was a Nicaraguan and a major leader of the FMLN (Farabundo Martí National Liberation Front) resistance movement in late-20th century El Salvador.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/DAS_Building_bombing">
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">DAS Building Terrorist Attack</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The DAS Building bombing was a truck bomb attack in Bogotá, Colombia, at 7:30 am on December 6, 1989. The bomb targeted the Administrative Department of Security (DAS) headquarters. A truck parked near the building exploded, killing 52 people and injuring about 1,000. The bomb blast, with an estimated 500 kg of dynamite, leveled several city blocks and destroyed more than 300 commercial properties. It is widely believed that the Medellín Cartel was responsible for the attack, in an attempt to assassinate DAS director Miguel Maza Márquez, who escaped unharmed. The same group was believed to be behind the bombing of Avianca Flight 203 the previous month. The DAS building bombing was the last in the long series of attacks that shook Colombia in 1989, starting January 18 with the killing of 12 judicial officials in Simacota (La Rochela massacre), and targeting politicians, magistrates, police officials and journalists.</skos:definition>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DAS_Building_bombing"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">DAS Building bombing</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Álvaro_Uribe">
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Alvaro Uribe Vélez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Alvaro Uribe Velez</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Álvaro_Uribe"/>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Álvaro Uribe Vélez (Spanish pronunciation: [ˈalβaɾo uˈɾiβe ˈβeles]; born 4 July 1952) is a Colombian politician who served as the 31st President of Colombia from 2002 to 2010. Uribe started his political career in his home department of Antioquia. He has held office in the Empresas Públicas de Medellín and in the Ministry of Labor and was the director of the Special Administrative Unit of Civil Aeronautics (1980–1982). Later he held office as the mayor of Medellín in 1982, then he was Senator between 1986 and 1994 and finally Governor of Antioquia between 1995 and 1997 before he was elected President of Colombia in 2002. Before his current role in politics Uribe was a lawyer. He studied law at the University of Antioquia and afterwards attended Harvard Extension School, where he received a Certificate of Special Studies in Administration and Management in 1993. In August 2010 he was appointed Vice-chairman of the UN panel investigating the Gaza flotilla raid. In 2012 Uribe and a group of political allies founded the Democratic Center movement to contest the 2014 national elections. He was elected senator in the 2014 parliamentary election and took office in July 2014.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Alvaro Uribe</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Álvaro Uribe Velez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Uribe alvaro</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Álvaro Uribe Vélez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Álvaro Uribe</skos:prefLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Lina Moreno de Uribe</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Uribe Velez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Lina Maria Moreno de Uribe</skos:altLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Carlos_Lehder">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Carlos Enrique Lehder Rivas or simply Carlos Lehder (born September 7, 1949) is a co-founder of the Medellin Cartel and former Colombian drug lord. He is currently imprisoned in the United States. Born in Armenia, Colombia, Lehder eventually ran a cocaine transport empire on Norman's Cay island, 210 miles (340 km) off the Florida coast in the central Bahamas. Lehder was one of the founding members of Muerte a Secuestradores ("MAS"), a paramilitary group whose focus was to retaliate against the kidnappings of cartel members and their families by the guerrillas.His motivation to join the MAS was to retaliate against the M-19 guerrilla movement, which, on November 19, 1981 attempted to kidnap him for a ransom, but he escaped from the kidnappers, and they only managed to shoot him in the leg.He was one of the most important MAS and Medellin Cartel operators, and is considered to be one of the most important Colombian drug kingpins to have been successfully prosecuted in the United States. Additionally, Lehder founded "a neo-Nazi political party", the National Latin Movement, whose main function, police said, appeared to be to force Colombia to abrogate its extradition treaty with the United States."</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Carlos Enrique Lehder Rivas</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Carlos Lehder-Rivas</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Carlos Leder</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Carlos Lehder Rivas</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Diego Delgado</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carlos_Lehder"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Carlos Lehder</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Alfonso_Patiño_Rosselli">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Alfonso Patiño Rosselli (1923 — 7 November 1985) was a Colombian jurist and diplomat who died in the 1985 Palace of Justice Siege by the M-19 where he was a Magistrate and President of the Constitutional Chamber of the Supreme Court of Colombia. He also served as the 10th Permanent Representative of Colombia to the United Nations, the 46th Minister of Finance and Public Credit of Colombia, Ambassador of Colombia to Uruguay, and Governor of Boyacá.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Alfonso Patino Rosselli</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Alfonso Patiño Roselli</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alfonso_Patiño_Rosselli"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Alfonso Patiño Rosselli</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/United_Self-Defense_Forces_of_Colombia">
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_Self-Defense_Forces_of_Colombia"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">United Self-Defense Units of Colombia</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">United Self-Defenders of Colombia</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">United Self-Defense Forces of Colombia</skos:prefLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Autodefensas Unidas de Colombia</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The United Self-Defenders of Colombia (Autodefensas Unidas de Colombia, or AUC, in Spanish) was a Colombian paramilitary and drug trafficking group which was an active belligerent in the Colombian armed conflict during the period from 1997 to 2006. The AUC was responsible for attacks against the FARC and ELN rebel groups as well as numerous attacks against civilians beginning in 1997 with the Mapiripán Massacre. The militia had its roots in the 1980s when militias were established by drug lords to combat rebel kidnappings and extortion. In April 1997 the AUC was formed through a merger, orchestrated by the ACCU, of local right-wing militias, each intending to protect different local economic, social and political interests by fighting left-wing insurgents in their areas. The organization was initially led by Carlos Castaño until his murder in 2004 and the organization was believed to have links to some local military commanders in the Colombian Armed Forces. The AUC had about 20,000 members and was heavily financed through the drug trade and through support from local landowners, cattle ranchers, mining or petroleum companies and politicians. The Colombian military has been accused of delegating to AUC paramilitaries the task of murdering peasants and labor union leaders, amongst others suspected of supporting the rebel movements and the AUC publicly and explicitly singled out 'political and trade union operatives of the extreme left' as legitimate targets. The AUC was designated as a terrorist organization by many countries and organizations, including the United States, Canada and the European Union. The bulk of the AUC's blocs demobilized by early 2006 and its former top leadership was extradited to the U.S. in 2008. However, local successors such as the Black Eagles continue to exist and death threats have been made using its name. On May 8, 2008, employees of a community radio station (Sarare FM Stereo) received a message stating: "For the wellbeing of you and your loved ones, do not meddle in subjects that do not concern the radio station. AUC, Arauca". A few days later the letters AUC were daubed on the front of their office. This threat was made due to their participation in a public meeting attended by members of a Congressional Human Rights Commission on the 27 September 2007. Here, members of the public denounced human rights abuses committed in Arauca Department by different parties to the armed conflict, including the AUC.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">United Self-Defence Forces of Colombia</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Self-Defense Units of Colombia</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Las Autodefensas Unidas de Colombia</skos:altLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/National_Opposition_Union">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">National Opposition Union (Unión Nacional Opositora—UNO) was a wide-range cartel of opposition parties formed to contest Nicaragua's president Daniel Ortega in the 1990 election. Its candidate Violeta Chamorro eventually won the race. UNO traced its origins back to the Nicaraguan Democratic Coordinating Group (Coordinadora Democrática Nicaragüense—CDN), which was formed in 1982 by different opposition groups. At the time of the election, of the UNO coalition's fourteen political parties, four were considered conservative, seven could be characterised as centrist parties, and three - including Nicaragua's Communists - had traditionally been on the far left of the political spectrum (see ). Despite internal struggle, the UNO coalition under Violeta Chamorro succeeded in its campaign centered on the economic downfall and promises of peace. Chamorro promised to end military draft, initiate democratic reconciliation, and restore economic growth. Many Nicaraguans felt that the contra war and bad economy would continue if the FSLN remained in power, because of the strong United States opposition to the FSLN (the Bush Administration had declared that it would only send aid to the government if the UNO was elected). Meanwhile, resources and organisational help were given to the UNO by the United States government's National Endowment for Democracy (NED), which in June 1989 had receive $2 million from U.S. Congress, which had also approved in April 1989 a package of $49.75 million in 'nonlethal' aid to the Contras, which funded their pro-UNO propaganda campaign. Some villages reported threats of murder from the Contras if they voted for the FSLN in the elections. In presidential election held on February 25, 1990, Violeta Barrios de Chamorro won 55% of the popular vote against Daniel Ortega's 41%. . The UNO disbanded in mid-1990s, after a very fractious rule during which little progress was made. The most positive consequence of their electoral victory was the end of the Contra War and the U.S. economic embargo.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Union Nacional Opositora</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/National_Opposition_Union"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">National Opposition Union</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Alberto_Santofimio">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Alberto Santofimio</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alberto_Santofimio"/>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Alberto Santofimio Botero (born June 17, 1942) is a Colombian politician, a member of the Colombian Liberal Party. He has been Minister of Justice, a two-time presidential candidate and a Senator. He was considered to be a sure bet for president in 1982, but he decided to let his boss, Alfonso López Michelsen who had been President from 1974 to 1978, run for reelection. In the 1990s, Santofimio was involved in the campaign Process 8000 as head of the Liberal Party in Tolima Department as that party's office was accused of receiving money from companies part of an investigation in order to support the campaign for the presidency of Colombia for Ernesto Samper. He was part of the 1990 pool of candidates for the presidency in the Liberal Party. After the assassination of another candidate, Luis Carlos Galán, he and the other members of the National Directive of the Liberal Party, decided to support César Gaviria, the campaign manager of Galán to be the sole Liberal Party candidate in 1990. During the investigations about the assassination of Luis Carlos Galán, Santofimio was mentioned as a rumour that he and other former presidencial candidates could have been involved in reference to influencing the crime. But he was cleared by the Attorney General and cousin of the assassinated candidate of any wrongdoing. Unfortunately for former Minister and Senator Santofimio, after 17 years a known criminal, Jhon Jairo Velásquez Vázquez a.k.a. "Popeye" and one of Medellin Cartel's Drug lords Pablo Escobar's lieutenants- in jail for most of his life, changed his original testimony given years before where he said Santofimio had nothing to do with the crime. However, Popeye decided to change his version, stating that perhaps Santofimio had influenced. On May 12, 2005, the investigation over Santofimio's role in the assassination of Galán started again, and he was arrested after new evidence surfaced. On October 2007 he was found guilty and sentenced to 24 years in prison. His attorneys immediately appealed the case before the State Supreme Court, the Tribunal Supremo de Justicia de Cundinamarca. A year later, on October 2008, a panel of 3 Supreme State Court Justices, citing lack of substantial evidence against the accused, overthrew the original judge's decision, and order Santofimio freed. The Court added that the credibility of the only witness against the accused, a hired assassin of Pablo Escobar's known as "Popeye," was highly controversial because he was a well-known criminal who had stated for 17 years, in various investigations, that Santofimio had nothing to do with the crime, and then had suddenly recanted his testimony. On August 31, 2011, however, the Colombian Supreme Court voided the State's Supreme Court decision and ratified the original sentence. The Court ordered Alberto Santofimio Botero's detention; he is now accused of being an influential part in the killing not only of Luis Carlos Galán, but also two other victims -- Julio Cesar Penaloza and Santiago Cuervo, who were gunned down along with Galán.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Alberto Santofimio Botero</skos:altLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/National_Police_of_Colombia">
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Policia Nacional de Colombia</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Colombian Police</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Police of Colombia</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Colombian national police</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/National_Police_of_Colombia"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Law enforcement in Colombia</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Colombia National Police</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The National Police of Colombia (Spanish: Policía Nacional de Colombia) is the national police force of Colombia. Although the National Police is not part of the Military Forces of Colombia (Army, Navy, and Air Force), it constitutes along with them the "Public Force" and is also controlled by the Ministry of Defense. They are the largest police force in Colombia. The force's official functions are to protect the Colombian nation, enforce the law by constitutional mandate, maintain and guarantee the necessary conditions for public freedoms and rights and to ensure peaceful cohabitation among the population. Colombians can communicate with the Police by calling toll free: 112 (nationwide) or 123 (from Bogotá, Bucaramanga, Cucuta, Pereira, Cali and Medellin). If it is regarding a kidnapping, the GAULA group can be reached at 165. They can also be contacted via the Internet to record suggestions, requests, questions, compliments or complaints using the "Sistema de Peticiones, Quejas, Reclamos y Sugerencias (PQRS)"</skos:definition>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">National Police of Colombia</skos:prefLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Colombian National Police</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Colombian police</skos:altLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Central_American_University">
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Central American University "Jose Simeon Canas"</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Universidad Centroamericana</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Universidad Centroamericana "Jose Simeon Cañas"</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">"Jose Simeon Canas" Central American University</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Universidad Centroamericana “José Simeón Cañas”</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">José Simeón Cañas Central American University</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Central American University "José Simeón Cañas"</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">“Jose Simeon Canas” Central American University</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Central_American_University"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Universidad Centroamericana "José Simeón Cañas"</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">José Simeón Cañas Central American University (Spanish: Universidad Centroamericana "José Simeón Cañas"), also known as UCA El Salvador, is a private university with nonprofit purposes in San Salvador, El Salvador, run by the Society of Jesus. It was founded on September 15, 1965, at the request of a group of Roman Catholic families who appealed to the Salvadoran government and the Society of Jesus in order to create another university as an alternative to the University of El Salvador, becoming the first private institution of higher education in the country. The Jesuits also run Central American University in Nicaragua (UCA Managua), opened in 1960.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Universidad Centroamericana "Jose Simeon Canas"</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Universidad Centroamericana “Jose Simeon Canas”</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">University of Central America</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jose Simeon Canas Central American University</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Central American University</skos:prefLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Universidad Centroamericana José Simeón Cañas</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">"José Simeón Cañas" Central American University</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Universidad Centroamericana Jose Simeon Canas</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">“José Simeón Cañas” Central American University</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jose Simeon Cañas Central American University</skos:altLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/José_Santacruz_Londoño">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">José Santacruz Londoño</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/José_Santacruz_Londoño"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jose Santacruz-Londono</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jose Santacruz Londono</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jose Santa Cruz Londono</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">José Santacruz-Londoño (1 October 1943 – 5 March 1996) was a Colombian drug lord. Along with Gilberto Rodríguez Orejuela and Miguel Rodríguez Orejuela, Santacruz-Londoño was a leader of the Cali Cartel. The trio was profiled in a TIME cover story in July 1991. Santacruz-Londoño and Rodríguez Orejuela brothers formed the Cali cartel in the 1970s. They were primarily involved in marijuana trafficking. In the 1980s they branched out into cocaine trafficking. For a time the Cali Cartel supplied 70% of the United States and 90% of the European cocaine market. The Cali Cartel was less violent than its rival, the Medellín Cartel. While the Medellín Cartel was involved in a brutal campaign of violence against the Colombian government the Cali Cartel grew. The cartel was much more inclined toward bribery rather than violence. However, after the demise of the Medellín Cartel the Colombian authorities turned their attention to the Cali cartel. The campaign began in the summer of 1995. Several Cali Cartel leaders were also arrested during the summer of 1995. Gilberto Rodríguez Orejuela was arrested on June 9. Miguel Rodriguez Orejuela was arrested on August 6. Santacruz Londoño was arrested on July 4, 1995. However, he escaped on January 11, 1996 La Picota Prison in Bogotá. The police tracked him down to Medellín on March 5, 1996. He was killed while attempting to flee.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Jorge_Luis_Ochoa_Vásquez">
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jorge Luis Ochoa Vazquez</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jorge_Luis_Ochoa_Vásquez"/>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Jorge Luis Ochoa Vásquez (born September 30, 1950) is a former Colombian drug trafficker who was one of the key members that founded the notorious Medellín Cartel in the late 1970s. The cartel's key members were Pablo Escobar, Carlos Lehder, José Gonzalo Rodríguez Gacha, Jorge Ochoa and his brothers Juan David and Fabio.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jorge Luis Ochoa</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Jorge Luis Ochoa Vásquez</skos:prefLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jorge Luis Ochoa Vasquez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jorge Luis Ochoa Vázquez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jorge Ochoa Vasquez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Ochoa brothers</skos:altLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Horacio_Serpa">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Horacio Serpa Uribe (born 3 January 1943) is a Colombian lawyer, politician and current Senator of Colombia. Serpa has run as the Colombian Liberal Party candidate for President of Colombia on three occasions; in 1998, 2002, and 2006. He previously served as congressman for Santander as Senator, Inspector General of Colombia, president of the National Constituent Assembly, Minister of the Interior, and as Ambassador of Colombia to the Organization of American States. He was also involved in the 8000 process scandal in which money from the Cali Cartel entered the presidential campaign of Liberal candidate Ernesto Samper. In 2007 Serpa ran for the governorship of Santander Department and was elected on October, 28 in the Colombian regional elections.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Horacio Serpa Uribe</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Horacio_Serpa"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Horacio Serpa</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Juan_Rafael_Bustillo">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Juan Rafael Bustillo</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Juan_Rafael_Bustillo"/>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Juan Rafael Bustillo (born January 31, 1935) is a former general and chief of the Air Force of El Salvador who is accused of planning the murder of six Jesuit priests, a housekeeper and her daughter at the Universidad Centroamericana "José Simeón Cañas" (UCA) in El Salvador on November 16, 1989. Bustillo was born in San Miguel in 1935 to John and Elena Toledo Bustillo. He entered the Salvadoran Military Academy on February 1, 1954, and was promoted to lieutenant in 1962, Captain in 1966, major in 1972, lieutenant colonel in 1976, colonel in 1980 and general in 1984. Bustillo is wanted in France for torturing, raping and murdering 27-year-old Madeleine Lagadec in El Salvador in 1989. Her raped, bullet-riddled body was found with its left hand severed. As the head of the Salvadoran Air Force, Bustillo oversaw the Contras' operation of importing weapons into Nicaragua that were paid for by crack cocaine smuggled into the United States. He is also accused of ordering Air Force officials to torture and murder members of the teachers union in El Salvador, including Maria Cristina Gomez. On November 13, 2008, The Center for Justice and Accountability (CJA) filed a criminal case in Madrid in Spain against former Salvadoran military officials, including Bustillo, for their role in the Jesuits Massacre of 1989. The CJA and their colleagues with the Spanish Association for Human Rights (APDHE) jointly filed the case as prosecutors in the Spanish National Court, using Spain’s universal jurisdiction law. On January 13, 2009, the 14 officers and soldiers named in the case were formally charged with crimes against humanity and state terrorism. Bustillo resides in El Salvador.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Luis_Otero_Cifuentes">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Luis Otero Cifuentes</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Luis_Otero_Cifuentes"/>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Luis Otero Cifuentes (Cali 1946 - Bogotá 1985) was a Colombian politician and guerrilla fighter. He was killed in the Palace of Justice siege in Bogotá.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/People&apos;s_Liberation_Movement_-_Cinchoneros">
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/People&apos;s_Liberation_Movement_-_Cinchoneros"/>
    <skos:definition>he Cinchoneros, also known as the Popular Liberation Movement (Spanish: Movimiento Popular de Liberación) was a militant organization active in the 1980s in Honduras. The MPL was one of the primary militant organizations in Honduras at the time, along with the Lorenzo Zelaya Popular Revolutionary Forces.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel>Popular Liberation Movement</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:prefLabel>Cinchoneros</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Salvatore_Mancuso">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Salvatore Mancuso</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Salvatore_Mancuso"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">El Mono Mancuso</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Triple Cero</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Mono Mancuso</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Santander Lozada</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Salvatore Mancuso Gómez, also known as "el Mono Mancuso","Santander Lozada" or "Triple Cero" (i.e. "Triple Zero", or, "000"), among other names (born August 17, 1964 in Montería, Córdoba) is a Colombian paramilitary leader, once second in command of the United Self-Defense Forces of Colombia (AUC) paramilitary group. The paramilitary groups commanded by Mancuso fought the guerrillas (mainly EPL, FARC and ELN), and financed their activities by receiving donations from land owners, drug trafficking, extortions and robbery. The AUC committed numerous atrocities and massacres against presumed guerrilla members and the civilian population. Mancuso was initially jailed in a Maximum Security Prison in Itagüí, Antioquia after a peace process that led to his demobilization and then transferred to a prison in the city of Cúcuta to help establish the whereabouts of some of the victims. In a surprise move by the Colombian government, Mancuso, along with 13 other top members of the AUC was extradited to the United States to stand trial on drug trafficking charges.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Dan_Quayle">
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Dan qualye</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">J. Danforth Quayle III</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dan_Quayle"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Dan Quale</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Dan Quail</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">William Figueroa</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">James Danforth "Dan" Quayle</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">James Danforth "Dan" Quayle (born February 4, 1947) is an American politician. He was the 44th Vice President of the United States, serving during the term of President George H. W. Bush (1989–93). He was also a U.S. Representative (1977–81) and U.S. Senator (1981–89) from the state of Indiana. Quayle was born in Indianapolis and spent most of his childhood living in Arizona. He married Marilyn Tucker in 1972 and obtained his J.D. from Indiana University School of Law – Indianapolis in 1974. He practiced law in Huntington, Indiana, with his wife before his election to the United States House of Representatives in 1976, aged 29. In 1980 Quayle won election to the Senate. In 1988, Vice President George H. W. Bush, the Republican Party nominee for the presidency, chose Quayle as his vice presidential running mate. The Bush/Quayle ticket won the 1988 election over Democrats Michael Dukakis and Lloyd Bentsen. As vice president, Quayle made official visits to 47 countries and was appointed chairman of the National Space Council. He secured re-nomination for vice-president in 1992, but Democrat Bill Clinton and his vice presidential running mate, Al Gore, defeated the Bush/Quayle ticket. In 1994, Quayle published his memoir entitled Standing Firm but declined to run for public office in this time period because he was suffering from phlebitis. He sought the Republican presidential nomination in 2000, but withdrew and supported George W. Bush. As of 2014 Quayle and his wife reside in Paradise Valley, Arizona. Quayle currently is the chairman of global investments at Cerberus Capital Management.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Quaylism</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Dan quayle</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Former Vice President Quayle’s</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Vice President Quayle</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">J. Danforth Quayle</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">James Danforth Quayle</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Danforth Quayle</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">J. "Dan" Quayle</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Danny Quayle</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Dan Quayle</skos:prefLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Dan quale</skos:altLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Colombian_Liberal_Party">
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Partido Liberal Colombiano</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Liberal Party of Colombia</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Liberal Party (Colombia)</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The Colombian Liberal Party (Spanish: Partido Liberal Colombiano; PLC) is a social-democratic political party in Colombia. It was originally founded as a liberal party, but later developed into a more social-democratic direction, joining the Socialist International in 1999.</skos:definition>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Colombian_Liberal_Party"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Colombian Liberal Party</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Angie_Sanclemente_Valencia">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Angie Sanclemente Valencia</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Angie_Sanclemente_Valencia"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Angie Sanselmente Valencia</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Angie Sansclemente Valencia</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Angie valencia</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Angie Sanclemente</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Angie Sanselmente Valencia also known as Angie Sanclemente Valencia (born 25 May 1979) is a former Colombian beauty queen and lingerie model believed to be the ringleader of one of the world's largest drug syndicates.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/The_Extraditables">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The Extraditables was an organization created by Colombian drug lords in the early 1980s. Their motto was: "We prefer a grave in Colombia to a prison in the United States." The aim of the group was to intimidate the Colombian government into banning extradition at the constitutional level (Colombia had a treaty of extradition with the United States) and they wanted to manipulate Colombian society into supporting their goal. Initially, the group simply published newspaper adverts in which they defended their position, and influenced political parties to speak in favour of their goals. However, over time their actions escalated into a war between the state and the drug cartel, with violent acts committed against politicians and members of law enforcement. Its members were largely drawn from the Medellin Cartel and others linked to the drug trafficking racket. Its principal leaders were: 
*  Pablo Escobar Gaviria, who was killed in 1993 on the roof of a house in Medellin. 
*  Gonzalo Rodríguez Gacha, who was killed by Colombian military personnel by a bullet to the face in 1989. 
*  Fabio Ochoa Vásquez, sentenced to 30 years in federal prison in the United States.</skos:definition>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Extraditables"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">The Extraditables</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/National_Army_of_Colombia">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The National Army of Colombia (Spanish: Ejército Nacional de Colombia) is the land military force of Colombia and the largest branch of the Colombian Armed Forces. It is responsible for carrying out land-based military operations along with the Colombian Naval Infantry (Infanteria de Marina) and for protecting the Colombian state against domestic or foreign threats. The modern Colombian Army has its roots in the Army of the Commoners (Ejército de los Comuneros), which was formed on the 7th of August of 1819, before the establishment of the present day Colombia to meet the demands of the Revolutionary War against the Spanish Empire. After their triumph against the Spanish, the Congress of Angostura created the Greater Colombian Army, to replace the disbanded Commoners Army.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Army of Colombia</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Colombian Army</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Colombian National Army</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Colombian army</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/National_Army_of_Colombia"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">National Army of Colombia</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vera_Grabe">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Vera Grabe</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vera_Grabe"/>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Vera Grabe Loewenherz is a Colombian anthropologist, politician, and former member of the Colombian guerrilla M-19, of which she was also a co-founder. She successfully rejoined society through a peace accord that permitted rebels to disarm and suffer no retaliation from the Government. Under the banner of the M-19 Democratic Alliance, a political party spin-off of the former armed group, she was elected to Congress, first as Representative of the Chamber, and then as Senator of Colombia. In the Colombian presidential election of 2002 she ran as Vice Presidential candidate for Luis Eduardo Garzón in the Social and Political Front ticket. She has worked as a diplomatic attachée on human rights with the Embassy of Colombia in Spain, Director of the NGO Observatorio para la Paz (1998–1999), professor and editor, and peace advocate.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Vera Grabe Loewenherz</skos:altLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Alfonso_López_Michelsen">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Alfonso López Michelsen (30 June 1913 – 11 July 2007) was the 24th President of Colombia from 1974 to 1978.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Alfonso López Michelson</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Lopez michelsen</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Alfonso Lopez Michelson</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Alfonso Lopez Michelsen</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alfonso_López_Michelsen"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Alfonso López Michelsen</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Carlos_Mauro_Hoyos">
    <skos:prefLabel>Carlos Mauro Hoyos Jiménez</skos:prefLabel>
    <skos:altLabel>Carlos Mauro Hoyos</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition>Carlos Mauro Hoyos Jiménez (Támesis, Antioquia, July 26, 1939 – Rionegro, Antioquia, January 25, 1988) was a Colombian jurist and politician. He was the general inspector of the nation from September 1987 until he was kidnapped and assassinated by hitmen under orders of Medellín Cartel.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Pablo_Escobar">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">(This article is about the Colombian drug lord. For other uses, see Pablo Escobar (disambiguation).)(This name uses Spanish naming customs: the first or paternal family name is Escobar and the second or maternal family name is Gaviria.)
Pablo Emilio Escobar Gaviria (December 1, 1949 – December 2, 1993) was a Colombian drug lord and drug trafficker. His cartel, at the height of his career, supplied an estimated 80% of the cocaine smuggled into the United States, turning over US $21.9 billion a year in personal income. Often called "The King of Cocaine", he was the wealthiest criminal in history, with an estimated known net worth of US $30 billion by the early 1990s (equivalent to about $54 billion today), making him one of the richest men in the world at his prime. Escobar was born in Rionegro, Colombia, and grew up in nearby Medellín. After briefly studying at Universidad Autónoma Latinoamericana of Medellín, he left without a degree and began to engage in criminal activity that involved selling contraband cigarettes, along with fake lottery tickets, and participated in motor vehicle theft. In the 1970s he began to work for various contraband smugglers, often kidnapping and holding people for ransom before beginning to distribute powder cocaine himself, as well as establishing the first smuggling routes into the United States, in 1975. His infiltration to the drug market of the U.S. expanded exponentially due to the rising demand for cocaine and, by the 1980s, it was estimated that 70 to 80 tons of cocaine were being shipped from Colombia to the U.S. on a monthly basis. His drug network was commonly known as the Medellín Cartel, which often competed with rival cartels domestically and abroad, resulting in high-rate massacres and the deaths of police officers, judges, locals and prominent politicians. In 1982, Escobar was elected as an alternate member of the Chamber of Representatives of Colombia as part of the Colombian Liberal Party. Through this, he was responsible for the construction of many hospitals, schools, and churches in western Colombia, which gained him popularity inside the local Roman Catholic Church, as well as with the locals of the towns he frequented. However, Escobar was vilified by the Colombian and American governments, due to the exploits of his political power, which resulted in Colombia becoming the murder capital of the world. Escobar was shot and killed by Colombian National Police, in his hometown, 24 hours after his 44th birthday.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Pablo escobar</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Pablo Escebar</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Pablo Escabar</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pablo_Escobar"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Pablo Emilio Escobar Gaviria</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Escobar (2009 film)</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Pablo Escobar Gaviria</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Pablo Escobar</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Augusto_Pinochet">
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Augusto José Ramón Pinochet Ugarte</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Augusto Pinchot</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Gen Augusto Pinochet</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Augustus Pinochet</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Augusto_Pinochet"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Augusto Pinoche</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Augusto Jose Ramon Pinochet Ugarte</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Augusto pinochet</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">General Augusto Pinochet</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Pinochet</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Augusto Pinochet</skos:prefLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">General Pinochet</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Augusto Pinochet Ugarte</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Pinochet Ugarte</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">GEneral aUGUsto PInocHet</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Augusto José Ramón Pinochet Ugarte (Spanish pronunciation: [auˈɣusto pinoˈ(t)ʃe] or [-ˈ(t)ʃet]; 25 November 1915 – 10 December 2006) was President of Chile between 1973 and 1990 and Commander-in-Chief of the Chilean Army from 1973 to 1998. He was also president of the Government Junta of Chile between 1973 and 1981. His rule of Chile was a dictatorship. Pinochet assumed power in Chile following a United States-backed coup d'état on 11 September 1973 that overthrew the democratically elected socialist Unidad Popular government of President Salvador Allende and ended civilian rule. Several academics have stated that the support of the United States was crucial to the coup and the consolidation of power afterward. Pinochet had been promoted to Commander-in-Chief of the Army by Allende on 23 August 1973, having been its General Chief of Staff since early 1972. In December 1974, the ruling military junta appointed Pinochet Supreme Head of the nation by joint decree, although without the support of one of the coup's instigators, Air Force General Gustavo Leigh. From the start of the new military government harsh measures were implemented. During the period of Pinochet's rule, various investigations have identified the murder of 1,200 to 3,200 people with up to 80,000 people forcibly interned and as many as 30,000 tortured. According to the Chilean government, the official number of deaths and forced disappearances stands at 3,095. Under the influence of the free market-oriented neoliberal "Chicago Boys", the military government implemented economic liberalization, including currency stabilization, removed tariff protections for local industry, banned trade unions and privatized social security and hundreds of state-owned enterprises. These policies produced what has been referred to as the "Miracle of Chile," but critics state that economic inequality dramatically increased and attribute the devastating effects of the 1982 monetary crisis on the Chilean economy to these policies. Chile was, for most of the 1990s, the best-performing economy in Latin America, though the legacy of Pinochet's reforms continues to be in dispute. Pinochet's 17-year rule was given a legal framework through a controversial 1980 plebiscite, which approved a new Constitution drafted by a government-appointed commission. In a 1988 plebiscite 56% voted against Pinochet's continuing as president, which led to democratic elections for the Presidency and Congress. After stepping down in 1990, Pinochet continued to serve as Commander-in-Chief of the Chilean Army until 10 March 1998, when he retired and became a senator-for-life in accordance with his 1980 Constitution. However, Pinochet was arrested under an international arrest warrant on a visit to London on 10 October 1998 in connection with numerous human rights violations. Following a legal battle he was released on grounds of ill-health, and returned to Chile on 3 March 2000. In 2004, Chilean Judge Juan Guzmán Tapia ruled that Pinochet was medically fit to stand trial and placed him under house arrest. By the time of his death on 10 December 2006, about 300 criminal charges were still pending against him in Chile for numerous human rights violations during his 17-year rule, and tax evasion and embezzlement during and after his rule; he was accused of having corruptly amassed at least $28 million USD.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Antonio_Navarro_Wolff">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Antonio José Navarro Wolff (born 9 July 1948) is a Colombian politician. He used to be a former Commandant and leader of the 19th of April Movement (M-19), a former guerrilla movement that operated in Colombia in the 1970s and 1980s. After the demobilization through a peace agreement of the M-19, Navarro and others formed the M-19 Democratic Alliance, a political party of which Navarro became a leader of entering mainstream politics in Colombia. In 1990 he ran as a M-19 political candidate during the Colombian presidential elections finishing third and receiving 12.48% of the votes; he ran again unsuccessfully in the 1994 presidential election, and attempted to run for the 2006 presidential elections but lost the candidacy of his party during the primaries. In 1991 he was elected to the National Constituent Assembly, of which became Co-President along with Álvaro Gómez Hurtado and Horacio Serpa Uribe; it was this Assembly that drafted the Colombian Constitution of 1991 which remains the supreme law of the country. He has also served in Congress, being elected to serve both in the Chamber from 1998 to 2002, and the Senate from 2002 to 2006; and elected Mayor of Pasto serving from 1995 to 1998, and Governor of Nariño from 2008 to 2012.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Antonio Navarro Wolf</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Antonio_Navarro_Wolff"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Antonio Navarro Wolff</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Griselda_Blanco">
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Cocaine Cowboy Wars</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Cocaine Queen</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Griselda blanco</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">The Godmother</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Griselda Blanco</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Griselda_Blanco"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Griselda Blanco Restrepo</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">("The Godmother" redirects here. For the biographical film based on Blanco's life, see The Godmother (film).) Griselda Blanco (February 15, 1943 – September 3, 2012), known as La Madrina, the Black Widow, the Cocaine Godmother and the Queen of Narco-Trafficking, was a Colombian drug lord of the Medellín Cartel and a pioneer in the Miami-based cocaine drug trade and underworld during the 1970s and early 1980s. It has been estimated that she was responsible for up to 200 murders while transporting cocaine from Colombia to New York, Miami and Southern California.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">The Godmother (book)</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">The Godmother: The True Story of the Hunt for the Most Bloodthirsty Female Criminal in Our Time, Griselda Blanco</skos:altLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/César_Gaviria">
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Cesar Gaviria Trujillo</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">(This name uses Spanish naming customs: the first or paternal family name is Gaviria and the second or maternal family name is Trujillo.) César Augusto Gaviria Trujillo (Spanish pronunciation: [ˈsesaɾ auˈɣusto ɣaˈβiɾja tɾuˈxiʝo]; born 31 March 1947) is an economist and Colombian politician. He was president of Colombia from 1990 to 1994, Secretary General of the Organization of American States from 1994 to 2004 and National Director of the Colombian Liberal Party from 2005 to 2009. During his tenure as president, he summoned the Constituent Assembly of Colombia that enacted the Constitution of 1991.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">César Augusto Gaviria Trujillo</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/César_Gaviria"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">César Gaviria Trujillo</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Cesar Gaviria</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Gaviria, Cesar</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Cesar Augusto Gaviria Trujillo</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">César Gaviria</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Palace_of_Justice_siege">
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Palace of justice siege</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Alfonso Plazas Vega Conspiracy</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Palace of Justice Siege</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Plazas' Trial</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The Palace of Justice siege (Toma del Palacio de Justicia in Spanish) was a 1985 attack against the Supreme Court of Colombia, in which members of the M-19 marxist guerrilla group took over the Palace of Justice in Bogotá, Colombia, and held the Supreme Court hostage, intending to hold a trial against President Belisario Betancur. Hours later, after a military raid, the incident left almost half of the 25 Supreme Court Justices dead. The military's role in the siege has been described as a holocaust and massacre by the Inter-American Commission on Human Rights.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Plazas' trial</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Colonel Alfonso Plazas</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Palace of Justice siege</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Palace_of_Justice_siege"/>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Los_Pepes">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Los Pepes</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Los_Pepes"/>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Los Pepes, a name derived from the Spanish phrase "Perseguidos por Pablo Escobar" ("Persecuted by Pablo Escobar"), was a short-lived vigilante group composed of enemies of drug lord Pablo Escobar. They waged a small-scale war against Escobar's Medellín Cartel in the early 1990s, which ended in 1993 with Escobar's death.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Los peppes</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Los pepyes</skos:altLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Peasant_Self-Defenders_of_Córdoba_and_Urabá">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Peasant Self-Defenders of Córdoba and Urabá</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peasant_Self-Defenders_of_Córdoba_and_Urabá"/>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Autodefensas Campesinas de Córdoba y Urabá (ACCU), Spanish for Peasant Self-Defenders of Córdoba and Urabá, was a paramilitary group formed in northwestern Colombia, operating mainly in the Antioquia Department and Córdoba Department. It was founded by Fidel Castaño, Carlos Castaño and Vicente Castaño to retaliate against the assassination of their father Jesús Castaño by FARC-EP guerrillas. The Colombian military had been supporting farmers' efforts by training some of them in military doctrine, which also had military veterans or retirees in their lines. The Army was authorized to do this following the Colombian constitutional article that supported civilian arming as self-defense against a threat to their rights, and the Castaño brothers as well as other farmers in the region had armed themselves and hired bodyguards following this principle. The military officially cut its links with these groups after finding out some of its members had ties to drug dealers. By 1994, several of these farmers had grouped together forming a small army to fight the guerrillas as part of the ACCU, led by Fidel Castaño and still being financed by drug dealers. The ACCU's first intentions were to protect their members' farms from being attacked by guerrillas and to defend those farmers' interests when threatened, including the protection of illegal drug crops and laboratories. The ACCU systematically eliminated left-wing sympathizers and peasant activists opposed to the farmers. After Fidel Castaño's disappearance, his brother Carlos took over the ACCU and eventually led it to the formation of the United Self-Defenders of Colombia (AUC), which grouped other small paramilitary armies organized throughout Colombia. Within the newly created AUC, Castaño's ACCU continued to be the most powerful force for most of its existence.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Autodefensas Campesinas de Cordoba y Uraba</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Peasant Self-Defense Forces of Córdoba and Urabá</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Cordoba and Uraba Peasant Self-Defense</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Cordoba and Uraba Peasants Self-Defense</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Peasant Self-Defense Forces of Cordoba and Uraba</skos:altLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Enrique_Parejo_González">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Enrique Parejo González</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Enrique_Parejo_González"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Enrique Parejo Gonzalez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Enrique Parejo González (born 1930) is a Colombian politician, ex justice minister, presidential candidate and prominent figure in Colombia since the 1970s. He was involved in a serious assassination attempt while being the Colombian ambassador in Hungary. Drug cartels were to blame for this actions.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Dandeny_Muñoz_Mosquera">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Dandeny Muñoz Mosquera</skos:prefLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Dandeny Munoz-Mosquera</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Dandenis Muñoz Mosquera</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Dandeny-Munoz Mosquera</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Dandeny Muñoz-Mosquera</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Dandeny Munoz Mosquera</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dandeny_Muñoz_Mosquera"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">La Quica</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Dandeny Muñoz Mosquera, also known as "La Quica" and to at least one DEA agent as "the Al Capone of the drug-murder circuit", was purported to be the chief assassin for the Medellín Cartel of Colombia. He was responsible for the deaths of an unknown number of people (estimates range in the hundreds), having supposedly murdered members of both the Medellín Cartel and the rival Cali Cartel, as well as police officers and government officials. Among his crimes is the 1989 bombing of Avianca Flight 203, which killed 110 civilians.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Victor_Patiño-Fomeque">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Victor Patiño-Fomeque</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Victor_Patiño-Fomeque"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Victor Patiño Fómeque</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Victor Patino-Fomeque</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Victor Julio Patiño-Fomeque aka El Quimico (the Chemist) is a Colombian narcotrafficker member of the Cali Cartel and Norte del Valle Cartel, currently serving time in a prison in the United States. Patino-Fomeque was responsible for ensuring the security and effectiveness of the Cali Cartel's maritime operations of drug shipments. He surrendered to Colombian authorities on June 24, 1995, and was sentenced to 12 years in prison. Patiño was once a Colombian policeman and was recruited later by Gilberto and Miguel Rodriguez Orejuela, leaders of the Cali Cartel, to be their bodyguard. On October 7, 2005, Patino and his mother testified in the United States and accused a prominent Colombian politician named Vicente Blel of being one of his major nominees. According to Patino, Blel met him under a fake name, Julio Gómez, to disguise his relation to the Cali Cartel and also said that he was a businessman from Cali willing to collaborate in the presidential campaign of Ernesto Samper. Patino was also personally introduced to Horacio Serpa, Samper's chief of debate back then. Blel responded that he indeed had met with Patino, thinking it was in fact Gomez, the businessman, and had collaborated with him several times, even helping him to put properties under his name and with numerous other favors. Patino and other members of the Cali Cartel used corruption as a way to protect their drug business. However, since he decided to testify in the U.S., he saw at least 35 family members and friends slaughtered in retaliation for his betrayal. Patiño-Fomeque was to be released on June 28, 2010, after serving six years in the United States prison system. The DEA decided it was best for Patiño-Fomeque to return to Colombia, since it wouldn't be fair for the US government to protect a criminal of his stature.Upon his return to Colombia, Patiño-Fomeque faces several homicide and extortion cases against him.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Alfonso_Reyes_Echandía">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Alfonso Reyes Echandía (14 July 1932 – 7 November 1985) was a Colombian educator, jurist and magistrate of the Supreme Court of Colombia who served as its President from 24 January 1985 until his death on the Palace of Justice siege.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Alfonso Reyes Echandia</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alfonso_Reyes_Echandía"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Alfonso Reyes Echandía</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Óscar_Romero">
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Óscar Arnulfo Romero y Galdámez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Óscar Arnulfo Romero y Galdámez (15 August 1917 – 24 March 1980) was a prelate of the Catholic Church in El Salvador, who served as the fourth Archbishop of San Salvador. He spoke out against poverty, social injustice, assassinations and torture. In 1980, Romero was assassinated while offering Mass in the chapel of the Hospital of Divine Providence. Pope Francis stated during Romero's beatification that "His ministry was distinguished by a particular attention to the most poor and marginalized." Hailed as a hero by supporters of liberation theology inspired by his work, Romero, according to his biographer, "was not interested in liberation theology", but faithfully adhered to Catholic teachings on liberation, desiring a social revolution based on supernatural interior reform. His spiritual life drew much from the spirituality of Opus Dei. In 2010, the United Nations General Assembly proclaimed 24 March as the "International Day for the Right to the Truth Concerning Gross Human Rights Violations and for the Dignity of Victims" in recognition of the role of Archbishop Romero in defence of human rights. Romero actively denounced violations of the human rights of the most vulnerable people and defended the principles of protecting lives, promoting human dignity and opposition to all forms of violence. In 1997, Pope John Paul II bestowed upon Romero the title of Servant of God, and a cause for beatification and canonization was opened for him. The cause stalled, but was reopened by Pope Benedict XVI in 2012. He was declared a martyr by Pope Francis on 3 February 2015, paving the way for his beatification, which took place on 23 May 2015. Latin American church groups often proclaim Romero an unofficial patron saint of the Americas and/or El Salvador; Catholics in El Salvador often refer to him as "San Romero". Even outside of Catholicism, Romero is honored by other Christian denominations, including Church of England and Anglican Communion through the Calendar in Common Worship, as well as in at least one Lutheran liturgical calendar. Archbishop Romero is also one of the ten 20th-century martyrs depicted in statues above the Great West Door of Westminster Abbey in London. In 2008, Europe-based magazine A Different View included Romero among its 15 Champions of World Democracy.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Óscar Arnulfo Romero</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Oscar Arnulfo Romero y Galdamez</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Óscar_Romero"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Cult of romero</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Archbishop Óscar Romero</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Óscar Romero</skos:prefLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Archbishop Romero</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Monsenor Romero</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Monseñor Romero</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Oscar Romero</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Oscar Arnulfo Romero</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Bishop romero</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Archbishop Oscar Romero</skos:altLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vinicio_Cerezo">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Vinicio Cerezo</skos:prefLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">President Vinicio Cerezo</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Vinicio Cerezo Arevalo</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vinicio_Cerezo"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Vinicio Cerezo Arévalo</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Marco Vinicio Cerezo Arevalo</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Marco Vinicio Cerezo Arévalo (born 26 December 1942) is a Guatemalan politician. He served as President of Guatemala from 14 January 1986 to 14 January 1991. He was the first president of the modern democratic era.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">President Cerezo</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Marco Vinicio Cerezo Arévalo</skos:altLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Gilberto_Molina">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Gilberto Molina (February 27, 1937 – February 27, 1989) was a major Colombian emerald magnate who was intimately connected to the notorious Medellín cartel and widely suspected of involvement in drug trafficking during the 1980s. During January 1988, Molina was charged with allegations that he operated an airplane maintenance facility at Subachoque, near Bogotá, where helicopters (including Panamanian registered helicopters) were serviced secretly. He also owned a private ranch called La Fortuna, which allegedly contained sophisticated warning devices and was used as a drug distribution center. Molina was at one time a close friend and working associate of José Gonzalo Rodríguez Gacha. Before Rodríguez Gacha attained his position as one of the top leaders of the Medellin cartel, he was employed in the service of Molina as his head of security. In January 1988, Molina was arrested on a murder charge and was later implicated as the owner of a 200-hectare coca plantation in Boyacá. However, the narcotics charges were later dropped. During 1989, he was involved in an intense power struggle over control of Colombia’s emerald mines, which are considered some of the richest in the world. Specifically, Molina was battling a rival operation, the Coscuez mines, in the violence-ridden emerald-mining district centered about 120 km northwest of Bogotá. Molina was initially assumed to be victorious in this violent struggle, along with his business partners Morita and Victor Carranza. However, any proclamation of victory soon proved to be premature. On Monday, February 27, 1989, a group consisting of around 25 uniformed men stormed into Molina’s luxurious ranch, located 72 km west of Bogotá, while Molina was hosting a housewarming party. The attackers took over the ranch without a fight and killed 18 men, including another emerald dealer, a retired police colonel in charge of Mr. Molina’s security, several bodyguards, friends and musicians. Colombian police officials speculated that the slaughter could have been on the orders of Rodríguez Gacha, who had made a failed attempt to elbow Molina out of the emerald profession. Despite the widespread suspicion of involvement in cocaine trafficking, Molina was also regarded as a public benefactor, spending nearly $500,000 on building a town hall, airport, a road and schools.</skos:definition>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gilberto_Molina"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Gilberto Molina</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Humberto_Ortega">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">General Humberto Ortega Saavedra (born January 10, 1947 in Managua) is a Nicaraguan military leader, often self-called leading Latin American revolutionary strategist, and published writer. He was Minister of Defense between the victory of the Sandinista revolution in 1979 under the National Reconstruction Government, through the first presidency of his brother Daniel Ortega Saavedra, and through the presidency of Violeta Barrios de Chamorro who defeated Daniel Ortega in the elections of 1990.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Humberto Ortega Saavedra</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Humberto_Ortega"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Humberto Ortega</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Patricio_Aylwin">
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Aylwin</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Patricio Aylwin Azócar (Spanish pronunciation: [paˈtɾisjo ˈelwin aˈsokar] ; November 26, 1918 – April 19, 2016) was a Chilean Christian Democrat politician, lawyer, author, professor and former senator. He was the first president of Chile after Pinochet, and his election marked the Chilean transition to democracy in 1990. Despite resistance from elements of the Chilean military and government after his election, Patricio Aylwin was staunch in his support for the Chilean Truth and Reconciliation Commission which exposed the Chilean government’s brutalities.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Aylwin Azocar</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Patricio Aylwin Azócar</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Patricio Ailwyn</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Patricio Aylwin</skos:prefLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Aylwin government</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Patricio Aylwin Azocar</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Patricio_Aylwin"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Aylwin administration</skos:altLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Kiki_Camarena">
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Enrique Camarena-Salazar</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">KiKi Camarena</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Enrique Camarena Salazar</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Enrique "Kiki" Camarena</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Enrique "Kike" Camarena</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Kiki Camarena</skos:prefLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Enrique Camarena (DEA agent)</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kiki_Camarena"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Enrique S. Camarena</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Enrique S. "Kiki" Camarena Salazar (July 26, 1947 – February 9, 1985) was a Mexican-born American undercover agent for the United States Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA) who was abducted on February 7, 1985, and then tortured and murdered, while on assignment in Mexico. Camarena's nickname was "Kike" in Spanish, and "Kiki" in English.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Enrique Camarena (DEA Agent)</skos:altLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Fidel_Castro">
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">El Commadante</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">El Comandante</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Fidel casro</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Fidel Alejandro Castro</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Fidel castro</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Phidel Castro</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Fidel Ruz</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Phidel castro</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Fidel Alejandro Castro Ruz</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Fidel Casto</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Castrophile</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Fidél Castro</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Castrist</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Fidel Castro</skos:prefLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Dr Castro</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">El lider maximo</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Fidel-Castro</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Fidelista</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Fidel Castro Ruz</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Fidel Catsro</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Castroist</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">(This name uses Spanish naming customs: the first or paternal family name is Castro and the second or maternal family name is Ruz.) Fidel Alejandro Castro Ruz (American Spanish: [fiˈðel aleˈxandɾo ˈkastɾo ˈrus] ; born August 13, 1926), commonly known as Fidel Castro, is a Cuban politician and revolutionary who governed the Republic of Cuba as Prime Minister from 1959 to 1976 and then as President from 1976 to 2008. Politically a Marxist–Leninist and Cuban nationalist, he also served as the First Secretary of the Communist Party of Cuba from 1961 until 2011. Under his administration Cuba became a one-party communist state; industry and business were nationalized, and state socialist reforms implemented throughout society. Born in Birán as the son of a wealthy farmer, Castro adopted leftist anti-imperialist politics while studying law at the University of Havana. After participating in rebellions against right-wing governments in the Dominican Republic and Colombia, he planned the overthrow of Cuban President Fulgencio Batista, launching a failed attack on the Moncada Barracks in 1953. After a year's imprisonment, he traveled to Mexico where he formed a revolutionary group, the 26th of July Movement, with his brother Raúl Castro and Che Guevara. Returning to Cuba, Castro took a key role in the Cuban Revolution by leading the Movement in a guerrilla war against Batista's forces from the Sierra Maestra. After Batista's overthrow in 1959, Castro assumed military and political power as Cuba's Prime Minister. The United States was alarmed by Castro's friendly relations with the Soviet Union, and unsuccessfully attempted to remove him by assassination, economic blockade, and counter-revolution, including the Bay of Pigs invasion of 1961. Countering these threats, Castro formed an alliance with the Soviets and allowed them to place nuclear weapons on the island, sparking the Cuban Missile Crisis—a defining incident of the Cold War—in 1962. Adopting a Marxist-Leninist model of development, Castro converted Cuba into a one-party socialist state under Communist Party rule, the first in the Western hemisphere. Reforms introducing central economic planning and expanding healthcare and education were accompanied by state control of the press and the suppression of internal dissent. Abroad, Castro supported anti-imperialist revolutionary groups, backing the establishment of Marxist governments in Chile, Nicaragua, and Grenada, and sending troops to aid allies in the Yom Kippur War, Ethio-Somali War, and Angolan Civil War. These actions, coupled with Castro's leadership of the Non-Aligned Movement from 1979–83 and Cuba's medical internationalism, increased Cuba's profile on the world stage and earned its leader great respect in the developing world. Following the Soviet Union's dissolution in 1991, Castro led Cuba into its "Special Period" and embraced environmentalist and anti-globalization ideas. In the 2000s he forged alliances in the Latin American Pink Tide—namely with Hugo Chávez's Venezuela—and signed Cuba to the Bolivarian Alliance for the Americas. In 2006 he transferred his responsibilities to Vice-President Raúl Castro, who formally assumed the presidency in 2008. Castro is a controversial and divisive world figure. He is decorated with various international awards, and his supporters laud him as a champion of socialism, anti-imperialism, and humanitarianism, whose revolutionary regime secured Cuba's independence from American imperialism. Conversely, critics view him as a totalitarian dictator whose administration oversaw multiple human-rights abuses, an exodus of more than one million Cubans, and the impoverishment of the country's economy. Through his actions and his writings he has significantly influenced the politics of various individuals and groups across the world.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Comandante Fidel</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">The maximum leader</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">F. Castro</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Lina Ruz</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fidel_Castro"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Order of Fidelity to the People</skos:altLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Luis_Carlos_Galán">
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Luis Carlos Galan Sarmiento</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Luis Carlos Galán Sarmiento</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Luis Carlos Galan</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">(This name uses Spanish naming customs: the first or paternal family name is Galán and the second or maternal family name is Sarmiento.) Luis Carlos Galán Sarmiento (29 September 1943 – 18 August 1989) was a Colombian journalist and liberal politician who ran for the presidency of Colombia on two occasions, the first for the Liberal Party in 1982, which he lost to Belisario Betancur. His poor results encouraged him to focus his aspirations on the political movement New Liberalism he had founded in 1979. The movement was initially the offspring of the mainstream Colombian Liberal Party but, with the mediation of former president Julio César Turbay, Galán returned to the party in 1987 and sought the nomination for the presidential election. Galán declared himself an enemy of the dangerous and influential Colombian drug cartels, mainly the Medellín Cartel led by Pablo Escobar (who had been part of his New Liberalism Movement) and Gonzalo Rodríguez aka "El Mexicano," that were corrupting Colombian society at all levels. Galán supported an extradition treaty with the U.S. After receiving several death threats, on August 18, 1989, Galán was shot to death by hitmen hired by the drug cartels during a public demonstration in the town of Soacha, Cundinamarca. At the time, he was comfortably leading in the polls for the forthcoming 1990 presidential election. The investigation into his assassination remains partially unsolved.</skos:definition>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Luis_Carlos_Galán"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Luis Carlos Galán</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Mario_Germán_Iguarán_Arana">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Mario Germán Iguarán Arana (born 8 June 1960) is a Colombian lawyer and diplomat. He served as Ambassador of Colombia to Egypt between 2010 and 2012. A lawyer, Iguarán has also served as the 3rd Deputy Minister of Justice of Colombia, the 5th Attorney General of Colombia, and as Assistant Magistrate of the Constitutional Court of Colombia.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Mario Iguaran</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Mario Iguarán</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Mario German Iguaran Arana</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mario_Germán_Iguarán_Arana"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Mario Germán Iguarán Arana</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Luis_Hernando_Gómez">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Luis Hernando Gómez</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Luis_Hernando_Gómez"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Hernando Gómez Bustamante</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Luis Hernando Gomez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Luis Hernando Gómez Bustamante</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Luis Hernando Gomez Bustamante</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Luis Hernando Gómez Bustamante (born March 14, 1958) is a Colombian drug trafficker for the Norte del Valle Cartel, who was arrested in 2004 and, on July 19, 2007 transported for extradition to the United States on charges of money laundering and drug smuggling. Gomez, also known as "Rasguño" (English: Scratch) is reported to have received his nickname after being grazed in the cheek by a bullet, he dismissed the wound as "just a scratch."</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/La_Catedral">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">La Catedral</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/La_Catedral"/>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">La Catedral was a prison overlooking the city of Medellín, in Colombia. The prison was built to specifications ordered by Medellín Cartel leader Pablo Escobar, under a 1991 agreement with the Colombian government in which Escobar would surrender to authorities and serve a maximum term of five years, and the Colombian government would not extradite him to the United States. In addition to the facility being built to Escobar's specifications, Escobar was also given the right to choose who would guard him, and it was believed he chose guards loyal only to him. Moreover, the prison was believed to have been designed more to keep out Escobar's enemies and protect him from assassination attempts, than to keep Escobar in. The finished prison was often called "Hotel Escobar" or "Club Medellín", because of its amenities. La Catedral featured a football pitch, giant doll house, bar, jacuzzi, and waterfall. Escobar also had a telescope installed that allowed him to look down onto the city of Medellín to his daughter's residence while talking on the phone with her. PBS reports that although the government was willing to turn a blind eye to Escobar's continuing his drug smuggling, the arrangement fell apart when it was reported Escobar had four of his lieutenants tortured and murdered within La Catedral. The Colombian government decided it had to move Escobar to a standard prison, an order Escobar refused. In July 1992, after serving one year and one month, Escobar again went on the run. With the Colombian National Army surrounding La Catedral's facility, it is said Escobar simply walked out the back gate. The ensuing manhunt employed a 600-man unit force, specially trained by the United States Delta Force, named Search Bloc and led by Colonel Hugo Martinez. Escobar was killed a year later, on December 2, 1993, in a shootout with members of Search Bloc when he was found hiding in a middle-class barrio in Medellín. As of 2007, La Catedral has been converted into a Benedictine monastery.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Club Medellin</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Hotel Escobar</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Club Medellín</skos:altLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Contras">
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Nicaraguan Contras</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Recontra</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Nicaraguan Contra</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Nicaraguan contras</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">The contras</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Contras"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Contra wars</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Contra (guerrillas)</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The contras (some references use the capitalized form, "Contras") is a label given to the various U.S.-backed and funded right-wing rebel groups that were active from 1979 to the early 1990s in opposition to the left-wing, socialist Sandinista Junta of National Reconstruction government in Nicaragua. Among the separate contra groups, the Nicaraguan Democratic Force (FDN) emerged as the largest by far. In 1987, virtually all contra organizations were united, at least nominally, into the Nicaraguan Resistance. From an early stage, the rebels received financial and military support from the United States government, and their military significance decisively depended on it. After US support was banned by Congress, the Reagan administration covertly continued it. These covert activities culminated in the Iran–Contra affair. The term "contra" comes from the Spanish contra, which means against but in this case is short for la contrarrevolución, in English "the counter-revolution". Some rebels disliked being called contras, feeling that it defined their cause only in negative terms, or implied a desire to restore the old order. Rebel fighters usually referred to themselves as comandos ("commandos"); peasant sympathizers also called the rebels los primos ("the cousins"). From the mid-1980s, as the Reagan administration and the rebels sought to portray the movement as the "democratic resistance," members started describing themselves as la resistencia. During their war against the Nicaraguan government, the Contras committed a large number of human rights violations and used terrorist tactics and carried out more than 1300 terrorist attacks. These actions were frequently carried out systematically as a part of the strategy of the contras. Supporters of the Contras tried to minimize these violations, particularly the Reagan administration in the US, which engaged in a campaign of white propaganda to alter public opinion in favor of the contras.</skos:definition>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Contras</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Enrique_Bernales_Ballesteros">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Enrique Bernales Ballesteros</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Enrique_Bernales_Ballesteros"/>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Enrique Bernales Ballesteros (born November 6, 1940, Lima) is a Peruvian scholar and politician. He was a member of the Peruvian Senate and the first UN Special Rapporteur on mercenaries. Bernales Ballesteros served as Principal Professor of Social Sciences at the Pontificia Universidad Católica del Perú (PUCP). He also served as the general secretary of the Revolutionary Socialist Party (PSR).</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Gustavo_Álvarez_Martínez">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Gustavo Álvarez Martínez</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gustavo_Álvarez_Martínez"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Gustavo Adolfo Álvarez Martínez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Gustavo Alvarez Martinez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Gustavo Adolfo Álvarez Martínez (12 December 1937 - 25 January 1989) was a Honduran military officer. He was head of the armed forces of Honduras from January 1982, being ousted on 31 March 1984 by fellow officers when he sought to expand his control over the armed forces. The notorious Honduran army unit Battalion 3-16, reporting directly to Álvarez Martínez, was active during this period, in which Honduras was a base for the Contras opposing the Sandinistas in neighbouring Nicaragua. Álvarez Martínez was awarded the Legion of Merit by the US government in 1983 for "encouraging the success of democratic processes in Honduras." In March 1984 he was ousted by fellow generals accusing him of abuses, and sent into exile. He became a consultant to The Pentagon, and lived in Miami until 1988, before returning to Honduras. Álvarez Martínez was assassinated in Honduras in 1989 by leftwing guerillas.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Nationalist_Republican_Alliance">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The Nationalist Republican Alliance (NRA) (Spanish: Alianza Republicana Nacionalista or ARENA) is a right-wing political party of El Salvador. It was founded on 30 September 1981, by Roberto D'Aubuisson and Mercedes Gloria Salguero Gross. ARENA controlled the National Assembly of El Salvador until 1985, and its party leader Alfredo Cristiani was elected to the presidency in 1989. ARENA controlled the presidency from 1989 until 2009. The party gained a plurality in the Legislative Assembly in 2012.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Alianza Republicana Nacionalista</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Alianza Republicana Nacionalista El Salvador</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">ARENA Party of El Salvador</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Republican Nationalist Alliance</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nationalist_Republican_Alliance"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Nationalist Republican Alliance</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Government_Junta_of_Chile_(1973)">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Government Junta of Chile (September 11, 1973 - March 11, 1990) (Spanish: Junta Militar de Gobierno) was the military junta established to rule Chile during the military dictatorship that followed the overthrow of President Salvador Allende in the 1973 Chilean coup d'état backed by the United States. It was the executive and legislative branch of government until December 17, 1974. After that date, it functioned strictly as a legislative body until the return to democracy in 1990.</skos:definition>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Government_Junta_of_Chile_(1973)"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Government Junta of Chile (1973)</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Henry_Loaiza-Ceballos">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Henry Loaiza-Ceballos</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Henry_Loaiza-Ceballos"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Henry Loaiza Ceballos</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Henry Loaiza-Ceballos aka El Alacran (The Scorpion) was a Colombian drug dealer part of the Cali Cartel. Loaiza was in charge mainly of the military apparatus of the organization, but was also involved in the shipment of drugs. He surrendered to Colombian authorities on June 19, 1995. On August 4, 2006 a higher tribunal of Ibagué attempted to free Loaiza after serving 11 of the 18 years sentence to prison for the conformation of illegal paramilitary groups in Valle del Cauca and Tolima Departments. The National Penitentiary and Prison Institute, (INPEC) asked the Attorney General's office and the DAS Security Service if Loaiza had any other judicial processes against him. A local attorney pertaining to the Life and Personal Integrity Unit in Ibagué ordered a warrant once again against Loaiza for homicide, production, traffic and possession of illegal weapons and munition. He was accused of participating in the murder of former Colombian Army captain Ignasio Luis Arteaga on April 28, 2004 in Ibagué. Captain Arteaga was Security Chief of a local company called Cooperative SERVIARROZ. Loaiza is currently serving his sentence in a prison in central Colombia located in the town of Cómbita, Boyacá. On December 19, 2006 Loaiza was again accused by Colombian authorities of being responsible for the homicide of more than 100 persons, after pressumably co-authoring the Massacre of Trujillo in the southern town of Trujillo, Valle del Cauca Department in order to benefit the Cali cartel and his shipments of drugs. Most of the bodies were thrown into the waters of the Cauca River.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Violeta_Chamorro">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Violeta Barrios Torres de Chamorro (born 18 October 1929) is a Nicaraguan politician, former president and publisher, known for ending the Contra War, the final chapter of the Nicaraguan Revolution, and bringing peace to the country. She was the first and, to date, only woman to hold the position of president in Nicaragua. Born into a landed family in southern Nicaragua, Chamorro was partially educated in the United States. After returning to her home country, she married and raised a family. Her husband, Pedro Joaquín Chamorro Cardenal, was a journalist working at his family's newspaper, La Prensa, which he later inherited. As a result of his anti-government stance, he was often jailed or exiled, forcing Chamorro to spend a decade following him abroad or visiting him in jail. When he was assassinated in 1978, Chamorro took over the newspaper. Pedro's murder sparked the Nicaraguan Revolution and his image, as wielded by his widow, became a powerful symbol for the opposition forces. Initially, when the Sandinistas were victorious over Anastasio Somoza García, Chamorro fully supported them. She agreed to become part of the provisional government established under the Junta of National Reconstruction (Spanish: Junta de Gobierno de Reconstrucción Nacional, JGRN); however, when the Junta began moving in a more radical direction and signed agreements with the Soviet Union, Chamorro resigned and returned to the newspaper. Under her direction, La Prensa continued to criticize the government and its policies despite threats and government-forced shutdowns. When Daniel Ortega announced that elections would be held in 1990, Chamorro was selected as the candidate for the opposition group known as the National Opposition Union (Spanish: Unión Nacional Opositora, UNO). This 14-party alliance ranged from conservatives and liberals to communists and because of idealistic differences had difficulty in devising any political platform other than a promise to end the war. Despite polls indicating a victory for the incumbent Sandinista President Ortega, Chamorro won the election on 25 February 1990, becoming the first elected female head of state in the Americas. When Chamorro was sworn in to office on 25 April 1990, it was the first time in more than five decades that a peaceful transition of power had occurred in Nicaragua and the first time that one elected president had given way to another. She inherited a hyperinflated, war-torn economy, but she was able to end the war and establish a lasting peace. Chamorro's leadership covered six difficult years marked by economic strife and social unrest, but she was able to compromise with rivals, maintain a constitutional regime, re-establish international banking relationships and end the hyperinflation that had plagued the country for several years. After leaving office on 10 January 1997, Chamorro worked on several international peace initiatives until poor health forced her to retire from public life.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Violeta Barrios de Chamorro</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Violeta B. de Chamorro</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Violeta Barrios Chamorro</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Violetta Chamorro</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Violeta_Chamorro"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Violeta Chamorro</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Rodrigo_Lara">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Rodrigo Lara Bonilla (August 11, 1946 – April 30, 1984) was a Colombian lawyer and politician, who served as Minister of Justice under President Belisario Betancur, and was assassinated by orders of Pablo Escobar because of his work as Minister in prosecuting cocaine traffickers mainly belonging to the Medellín Cartel. Lara's death led to Escobar's indictment for murder and a long running controversy over extradition in Colombia that would ultimately cost thousands of lives.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Lara Bonilla</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Rodrigo Lara Bonilla</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rodrigo_Lara"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Rodrigo Lara</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Fuerzas_Populares_de_Liberación_Farabundo_Martí">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Fuerzas Populares de Liberación Farabundo Martí</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fuerzas_Populares_de_Liberación_Farabundo_Martí"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Fuerzas Populares de Liberacion Farabundo Marti</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Farabundo Martí Liberation People's Forces</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Fuerzas Populares de Liberación</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Fuerzas Populares de Liberación "Farabundo Martí"</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Fuerzas Populares de Liberación “Farabundo Martí”</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The Fuerzas Populares de Liberación "Farabundo Martí" (FPL) (English: Farabundo Martí Liberation People's Forces) was a left wing guerrilla military and political organization in El Salvador. It was the oldest of the five groups who in 1980, merged to form the Frente Farabundo Martí para la Liberación Nacional (FMLN).</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Omar_Torrijos">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Omar Efraín Torrijos Herrera (February 13, 1929 – July 31, 1981), more commonly known as Omar Torrijos, was the Commander of the Panamanian and National Guard and the de facto dictator of Panama from 1968 to 1981. Torrijos was never officially the president of Panama, but instead held titles including "Maximum Leader of the Panamanian Revolution" and "Supreme Chief of Government." Despite taking power in a coup d'état, Torrijos instituted a number of social reforms and his regime was considered progressive. Torrijos is best known for negotiating the 1977 Torrijos–Carter Treaties that eventually gave Panama full sovereignty over the Panama Canal. The two treaties guaranteed that Panama would gain control of the Panama Canal after 1999, ending the control of the canal that the U.S. had exercised since 1903. On December 31, 1999, the final phase of the treaty, the US relinquished control of the Panama Canal and all areas in what had been the Panama Canal Zone. His son Martín Torrijos was elected president and served from 2004 to 2009.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Torrijos Herrera</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Omar Efrain Torrijos Herrera</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">El supremo supremo</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Omar_Torrijos"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Omar Efraín Torrijos Herrera</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Omar Torrijos Herrera</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Maximum Leader of the Panamanian Revolution</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Omar Torrijos</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Andrés_Pastrana_Arango">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Andrés Pastrana Arango (born 17 August 1954) was the 30th President of Colombia from 1998 to 2002, following in the footsteps of his father, Misael Pastrana Borrero, who was president from 1970 to 1974. Until 2016, he is the last president from the Conservative Party.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Andrés Pastrana</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Andres Pastrana</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Andres Pastrana Arango</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Andrés_Pastrana_Arango"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Andrés Pastrana Arango</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Colombian_Communist_Party">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The Colombian Communist Party (in Spanish: Partido Comunista Colombiano) or PCC is the legal communist party of Colombia. It was founded in 1930, as the Colombian section of the Comintern. It is currently led by Jaime Caycedo. The PCC is part of the Social and Political Front (FSP) party coalition and, as August 2012, no longer participates in the Alternative Democratic Pole (PDA) alliance since the expelling of its members due to statutory infringement, namely, multiple affiliation to other parties. PCC publishes the weekly newspaper Voz.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Partido Comunista Colombiano</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Colombian_Communist_Party"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Colombian Communist Party</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Hugo_Martínez">
    <skos:prefLabel>Hugo Martínez</skos:prefLabel>
    <skos:altLabel>Hugo Martinez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition>Hugo Martínez (born 1941) is a retired Colombian police general. He was assigned the new commander of the Search Bloc, a unit of the National Police of Colombia assembled by President César Gaviria in 1992; and tasked with the sole objective of the apprehension of drug lord Pablo Escobar and his associates.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Guatemalan_National_Revolutionary_Unity">
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">United Guatemalan National Revolutionaries</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">National Guatemalan Revolutionary Unity</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Guatemalan National Revolutionary Unity</skos:prefLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">URNG-MAIZ</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The Guatemalan National Revolutionary Unity  (in Spanish: Unidad Revolucionaria Nacional Guatemalteca, URNG-MAIZ or most commonly URNG) is a Guatemalan political party that started as a guerrilla movement but laid down its arms in 1996 and became a legal political party in 1998 after the peace process after the Guatemalan Civil War.</skos:definition>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Guatemalan_National_Revolutionary_Unity"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Unidad Revolucionaria Nacional Guatemalteca</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">URNG</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Guatemalan National Revolutionary Unit</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Guatemalan National Revolutionary Union</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Guatemalan National Revolucionary Unity</skos:altLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Andre_Melendez">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Andre Melendez</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Andre_Melendez"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Angel Melendez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Andre Melendez (c. May 1, 1971 – March 17, 1996), better known as Angel Melendez, was a member of the Club Kids and purported drug dealer who lived and worked in New York City. Melendez and his family arrived in New York from Colombia when Melendez was eight years old. Melendez purportedly became a drug dealer during the early 1990s after he met Peter Gatien, owner of the Limelight Club in New York, becoming a regular dealer in Gatien's clubs. He was frequently seen at Manhattan clubs wearing his signature feathered wings. Melendez met Michael Alig, a night club party promoter. Alig became an important customer, leading Melendez to the world of the Club Kids, including James St. James and DJ Keoki. Melendez was killed by Alig and Robert "Freez" Riggs after purportedly going to Alig's apartment to collect on a delinquent drug debt. He was hit on the head with a hammer, restrained with duct tape and either injected with or forced to drink Drano. Later his body was dismembered and dumped in the Hudson River. At first, Alig claimed it was self-defense, but later admitted to the killing. On October 1, 1997 Michael Alig and Robert Riggs were sentenced to ten to twenty years in prison for Melendez's killing after each pleaded guilty to one count of manslaughter. Alig's killing of Angel Melendez is documented in the memoir Disco Bloodbath, written by James St. James. The book chronicled the life of Michael Alig and the Club Kids. A 1998 documentary film titled Party Monster: The Shockumentary was based on the events leading up to and surrounding his killing. A feature film titled Party Monster was later released, starring Wilson Cruz in the role of Melendez. His killing was also covered in an episode of Investigation Discovery's Deadly Devotion. Robert Riggs was released from prison in 2010. Michael Alig was released from prison on May 5, 2014.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Avianca_Flight_203">
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">La Quica plane bombing</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Avianca Airlines Flight 203 was a Colombian domestic passenger flight from El Dorado International Airport in Bogotá to Alfonso Bonilla Aragón International Airport in Cali. It was destroyed by a bomb over the municipality of Soacha on November 27, 1989. The aircraft took off from the Colombian capital Bogotá en route to Cali. It was in the air for five minutes and flying at a speed of 794 kilometres per hour (493 mph) when an explosive charge detonated on board, igniting fuel vapors in an empty fuel tank.</skos:definition>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Avianca_Flight_203"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Avianca Flight 203</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Juan_Carlos_Ortiz_Escobar">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Juan Carlos Ortiz Escobar aka Cuchilla was a Colombian drug dealer and prominent member of the Cali Cartel. Ortiz-Escobar was a nephew of former Medellin Cartel boss Pablo Escobar. Ortiz-Escobar surrendered to Colombian authorities on March 1996 to take advantage of a reduction of sentence in exchange for turning himself in and admitting his guilt. After the capture of Norte del Valle Cartel kingpin Juan Carlos Ramirez Abadia on August 7, 2007, Brazilian authorities discovered he had close ties to Ortiz-Escobar. Ramirez-Abadia had been helped by Ortiz-Escobar to establish himself in Brazil. Ortiz-Escobar was killed in 2002, after getting out of jail, by orders of Wilber Varela aka Jabón.</skos:definition>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Juan_Carlos_Ortiz_Escobar"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Juan Carlos Ortiz Escobar</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Guillermo_Cano_Isaza">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Guillermo Cano Isaza (12 August 1925 – 17 December 1986) was a Colombian journalist.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Guillermo Cano</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Guillermo_Cano_Isaza"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Guillermo Cano Isaza</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vicente_Castaño">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Vicente Castaño</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vicente_Castaño"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Vicente Castano</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Vicente Castaño Gil</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Vicente Castano Gil</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">José Vicente Castaño Gil aka El Profe (born July 2, 1957) is a Colombian paramilitary former leader of the United Self-Defense Forces of Colombia (AUC), a right-wing Colombian paramilitary organization. After demobilizing, he was accused of murdering his brother and former AUC leader Carlos Castaño and of narcotics trafficking by both the Colombian government and the government of the United States. In August 2004, the United States formally requested his extradition. Castaño remains, however, a fugitive and is the presumed chief of the criminal organization Águilas Negras made up of former AUC paramilitary members.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Carlos_Alberto_Rentería_Mantilla">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Carlos Alberto Rentería Mantilla</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carlos_Alberto_Rentería_Mantilla"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Carlos Alberto Renteria</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Carlos Alberto Renteria Mantilla</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Beto Rentería</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Beto Renteria</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Carlos Alberto "Beto" Rentería Mantilla (born March 11, 1945 in Tuluá, Valle del Cauca) is a former Colombian narcotrafficker and crime boss, presumed leader of the Norte del Valle Cartel. Rentería is believed by the United States government to be holding a leadership position within the drug cartel, he has been labeled "one of Colombia's most powerful and sophisticated narcotics traffickers" by Adam Szubin, Director of the Office of Foreign Assets Control, United States Department of the Treasury. The Attorney General of Colombia and the Colombian National Police accuse Rentería of narcotrafficking and money laundering.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Medellín_Cartel">
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Medillín cartel</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Medellin Cartel</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Medellín drug cartel</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Medellín Cartel</skos:prefLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The Medellín Cartel was an organized network of drug suppliers and smugglers originating in the city of Medellín, Colombia. The drug cartel operated throughout the 1970s and 1980s in Bolivia, Colombia, Honduras, Peru, and the United States, as well as in Canada and Europe. It was founded and run by Ochoa Vázquez brothers Jorge Luis, Juan David, and Fabio, together with Pablo Escobar, George Jung, Carlos Lehder and José Gonzalo Rodríguez Gacha. By 1993, the highly effective resistance group, Los Pepes (or PEPES), controlled by the Cali Cartel, and the Colombian government, in collaboration with the Cali Cartel, right-wing paramilitary groups, and the United States government, had dismantled the Medellín Cartel by imprisoning or assassinating its members. At the height of its operations, the Medellín Cartel smuggled tons of cocaine each week into countries all over the world and brought in at least $420,000,000 per week. For a time, the Medellín Cartel supplied at least 84% of the United States and 80% of the global cocaine market.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Medillín Cartel</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Medellín_Cartel"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Medellin cartel</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Medellín cartel</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Medellin drug cartel</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Cartel De Medellin</skos:altLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/José_Alfredo_Martínez_de_Hoz">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">José Alfredo Martínez de Hoz</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/José_Alfredo_Martínez_de_Hoz"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jose Alfredo Martinez de Hoz</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Jose Martinez de Hoz</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Martínez de Hoz</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Martinez de Hoz</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">José Alfredo Martínez de Hoz (13 August 1925 – 16 March 2013) was an Argentine executive and policy maker. He served as Minister of the Economy under de facto President Jorge Rafael Videla between 1976 and 1981, and shaped economic policy during the National Reorganization Process military dictatorship.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Joaquín_Vallejo_Arbeláez">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Joaquín Vallejo Arbeláez</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joaquín_Vallejo_Arbeláez"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Joaquin Vallejo Arbelaez</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Joaquín Vallejo Arbeláez (2 October 1912 — 31 December 2005) was a Colombian civil engineer, businessman and writer who served as 12th Permanent Representative of Colombia to the United Nations, and held various ministries during the Military Junta and the National Front in Colombia. As Colombian Minister of Foment in 1957 during the administration of General Gabriel París Gordillo, he helped design and implement the mechanism that would eventually become known as the Vallejo Plan, a business plan that would allow Colombian companies to import raw materials, specialized equipment, and industrial machinery with duty-free exemptions or lowered tariffs, if those materials and/or equipment would go towards producing marketable exporting goods, as an incentive to industrialize the national economy and open up to international markets.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Camilo_Torres_Restrepo">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Camilo Torres Restrepo</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Camilo_Torres_Restrepo"/>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Camilo Torres Restrepo (3 February 1929 in Bogotá, Colombia – 15 February 1966 in Santander) was a Colombian socialist, Roman Catholic priest, a predecessor of liberation theology and a member of the National Liberation Army (ELN) guerrilla organisation. During his life, he tried to reconcile revolutionary Marxism and Catholicism. As part of the academic staff of the National University of Colombia, he was a co-founder of the Sociology Faculty together with Orlando Fals Borda in 1960. His involvement in several student and political movements during the time won him a large following as well as many detractors, especially from the Colombian government and the church itself. Due to the growing pressure to back down from his radical politics, Camilo Torres saw himself persecuted and went into hiding (leaving his job as an academic) by joining the guerrillas in Colombia.He served as a low-ranking member of the ELN to whom he also provided spiritual assistance and inspiration from a Marxist-Christian point of view. He was killed in his first combat experience, when the ELN ambushed a Colombian Military patrol. After his death, Camilo Torres was made an official martyr of the ELN. He is perhaps best known for the quote: "If Jesus were alive today, He would be a guerrillero." In the Dominican Republic in 1970 a revolutionary group that included catholic clergy members and university students was founded under the name CORECATO which stood for Comando Revolucionario Camilo Torres or Revolutionary Command Camilo Torres. In New York City, San Romero of the Americas Church-UCC has founded the Camilo Torres Project in 2009. This project works for social justice and peace for the people of the Washington Heights community. He was a life-long friend of fellow socialist Luis Villar Borda.</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Camillo Torres Restrepo</skos:altLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Belisario_Betancur">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Belisario Betancur</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Belisario_Betancur"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Belisario Betancourt</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Belisario Betancur Cuartas</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Belisario Betancur Cuartas (born February 4, 1923) is a former Colombian politician and the 26th President of Colombia from 1982 to 1986. He is a member of the Colombian Conservative Party.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Tomás_Medina_Caracas">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Tomás Medina Caracas</skos:prefLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tomás_Medina_Caracas"/>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Negro Acacio</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Tomas Molina Caracas</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Tomas Medina Caracas</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Tomás Medina Caracas also known as Tomás Molina Caracas and Negro Acacio (March 15, 1965 – September 1, 2007) was a Colombian guerrilla member of the Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia (FARC) considered by Colombian authorities the man in charge of the illegal drug trade business and the head of the Eastern Bloc's 16th Front of this rebel group. He gained notoriety during the FARC-Government peace process (1999-2002) acting as a negotiator. He was also known for being the associate of Brazilian drug dealer Fernandinho Beiramar and for participating in an illegal arms deal of 10,000 AK-47s for the FARC through the Peruvian government official Vladimiro Montesinos, an adviser of former president of Peru, Alberto Fujimori. Medina Caracas was killed on September 1, 2007 in a Colombian Army military operation in eastern Colombia within the municipality of Cumaribo near the border with Venezuela. Medina Caracas had between 17 and 23 legal processes pending with the Attorney General of Colombia, requesting his capture and a red corner notice issued by the INTERPOL. The Colombian Army spent two years searching for Medina Caracas, with him escaping from most of the operations carried out to find him. Just in Colombia, Medina Caracas was charged with narcotrafficking, delinquency, kidnapping, torture, first degree murder, terrorism, extortion and robbery.</skos:definition>
  </skos:Concept>
  <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Rafael_Leonardo_Callejas_Romero">
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Rafael Leonardo Callejas Romero (born November 14, 1943) was the President of Honduras from 27 January 1990 to 27 January 1994, representing the National Party of Honduras (PNH).</skos:definition>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Rafael Callejas</skos:altLabel>
    <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Rafael Leonardo Callejas</skos:altLabel>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rafael_Leonardo_Callejas_Romero"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Rafael Leonardo Callejas Romero</skos:prefLabel>
  </skos:Concept>
</rdf:RDF>
